I just woke up.
Didn't even brush my teeth yet.
I may have to take a break and brush my teeth in a bit.
But I just ate.
So I'm gonna have to wait a little bit.
What's going on, eh?
I've got my coffee, yes.
What can I say, guys?
I'm sorry, I just... I really felt like Minecraft.
Like, I was gonna stream Minecraft today, but I wanted to play now.
So I'm playing now.
And I guess the people that usually can't watch...
They get to watch now.
Cheers.
Happy Sunday.
Yes, this will be a 27-hour stream.
Nah, 27 is too much.
I don't think I can even do that anymore.
I'm too old, man.
I actually don't have the physical stamina to play games for over 24 hours.
Unless it's World of Warcraft.
Then I can go for 48.
Did you wash the bread for breakfast, Oliver?
I've made some mods for my games using Claude.
It's cool times.
I know, right?
Such a weird frickin' time we live in.
It is so much fun to just play around with.
I'm having a blast.
Rip ads.
Well, I'm glad ads are playing now.
Because that means ads are not gonna play when I start.
That's good.
Saying that.
Pretending like I didn't just...
Fully just activate ads.
No, I didn't.
Why do I even lie to make myself look like that?
Doesn't even make sense.
Is music is nostalgic?
Yeah, for me as well.
Really like Persona 5.
Although I never finished it.
Maybe one day.
How do I become a super smart guy like you?
I'm not that smart.
Jojo Map.
At least I don't think so.
I think I'm pretty much at the top of the bell curve, you know?
I'm pretty average.
I have my moments.
And I definitely also have my, let's just say, other moments.
And it all averages out.
New YouTube series in mind?
There may be something coming soon.
Something that is a little out of left field maybe, and...
Something you probably wouldn't expect from me.
But not in the way that, oh, you would never expect a game like that.
It's something else.
You'll see what I mean.
It's...
Maybe in like...
I don't know.
I'm not gonna put a date on it, but...
Let's just say we have something planned.
Me and my team.
I have a whole team hired now, by the way.
I don't know if you knew that.
I'm not even playing anymore.
I'm just sitting with a mic in like a little broom closet, and someone else is controlling.
And then I do the voiceover.
It's awesome.
He needs to lie.
I'm sorry.
Oliver's IQ is a...
X times sine 1 over X function?
I mean...
I maybe agree with that.
I can't visualize that right now, in my head.
But if it's something that goes up and down, then it's probably right.
Please do stream in YouTube.
Nah, I'm streaming on Twitch now.
I don't wanna multi-stream.
Maybe one day...
If Twitch, like, goes down, or...
It becomes shit, you know?
I mean, it already kinda is, but you know what I mean?
Like, even worse.
Like, really terrible.
Then we'll probably go back to YouTube.
The thing is, though, YouTube saves a VOD, and...
I don't know, man.
I like being able to adjust volumes in post when I put the VOD on YouTube, you know?
So, like, if the music was too loud, or my voice was too low, I can adjust that before I upload the VOD to YouTube.
It's nice having that freedom.
Really enjoy it.
Going all in on Persona music.
So how you guys doing?
What are you guys doing right now?
What time is it?
Are you early or late?
Also, are some of you here that normally can't catch the stream?
Because I'm streaming early.
Or late, depending on who you are.
Yes?
It's 1am, I was playing KSP!
Bro, I shit you not, if I wasn't streaming that game, I would be playing it even more.
You know?
Like, I would be thinking about it all the time, and playing it all the time.
I'm kind of restraining myself a little bit.
That game is so much fun.
Wake up at 1, 4pm, 5...
Oh my god, there's people from all over!
2pm, 359...
Wow.
That's crazy.
You guys gotta go to sleep, man!
If it's that late.
Come on.
Don't make the mistake.
Watch the VOD.
It's gonna mess up your sleep rhythm.
It's a bad idea, trust me.
It's 1am, what are you doing to us?
I'm not doing anything.
I'm just...
I'm just gonna play my game.
And I'm gonna have fun.
I'm gonna enjoy it.
I'm gonna enjoy my hot coffee.
Oh man, it's actually so nice.
My hands are cold, and I'm just clutching the cup right now.
It is so cozy.
Can you send me your mod pack?
It's really simple.
It's just create, and aeronautics, and...
I mean, other than the mod I have for the progression, it's pretty much just that.
You know?
Yeah, the blue book mod.
That's the only real custom one.
The rest is just create, really.
Pretty simple.
Oh, and Jenny mod.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're right, Jen.
By the way, I saw you changed your profile name on Discord, Jen.
And for a second, I was like...
How could you have done this?
And then I looked at it, and it was still an owl.
I was like, okay, okay, it's fine.
I'll allow it.
I thought it was something other than an owl.
And I got upset.
Good gaming, Oliver.
Today is good stream.
Wait, this sounds like a bot writing, Mik Sufi.
Are you a bot?
You haven't even seen me game yet, today.
It's the spooky version that my friend made for me in 2020.
Yeah, I noticed it was because of the Halloween, I guess.
If you like dark UI, Vanilla Tweaks has a nice dark UI texture pack.
Honestly, the UI in Minecraft for me is perfect.
As it is.
It's genuinely, like, perfect.
Except for a couple small things, of course.
But, like, overall, I would say I love the simplicity of it.
I love just the way it looks and feels.
It's amazing.
Are you a bot?
Um...
No.
I'm not.
Hopefully, you bought that.
Is your team a bot?
I don't actually have a team.
The only one on my team is Jackie, and she's posting notifications for my videos.
And in return, she gets a home.
She gets all the snacks she could ever want.
She gets all the beds and toys and all the cuddles.
I think that's a good exchange.
Oh my god, Jackie is a bot.
Imagine we get to a future where we get, like, bot pets.
I think that would be kind of weird.
But I think there's a market for it.
You know, people who don't wanna...
Clean up after the pets or...
You know...
Pets that are, like, very, um...
What do you call it?
Intensive when it comes to taking care of them.
You know, like, lizards or something.
That require very specific temperatures and all that stuff.
I think those exist already.
Really?
But, like, not convincingly though, right?
Wait, there's no way we have that.
What do you mean?
Isn't robot pet a real thing?
I'm talking about, like...
Something that could...
You know, be mistaken for a real cat.
We don't have that.
You know?
Not that I ever wanna...
Jackie, close your ears.
I would never replace you.
You are the real Jackie.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like, fully...
Like, you know, um...
Detroit become human style.
Cats.
You know?
Or dogs.
Whatever.
That hasn't been the real Jackie for quite some time.
Oh, man.
Don't say that.
Nah, I know...
I...
I would know my Jackie.
I would know if she got replaced.
I can tell.
How do people eat Bulldog Instant Ramen too?
Yeah, right?
I like to just say that randomly.
But...
My sister, my youngest sister...
She loves that.
And she eats it all the time.
And I don't understand how the hell she's doing it.
Like, I consider myself like a chili guy.
I...
I'll eat spicy food, you know?
But that...
That is like...
Borderline making me sick.
It's too much.
But yeah, I guess she's kind of an alien.
I love spicy food, but I always regret it later.
I actually never have an issue with that.
But I know a lot of people do.
For some reason, when I eat pizzas with...
Jalapenos on it.
Like really spicy ones.
Then my butt hurts the next day.
But any other thing?
Like chilies with normal chilies?
No.
Not really.
It's weird.
It's always pizza with jalapenos.
That does it for me.
The Ring of Fire, yeah.
Ring sting.
Lava butt.
Dude, I'm freaking...
Just...
Inhaling this coffee right now.
I need to calm down.
Would you rather never eat bread again or never eat rice again?
Never eat rice again.
I don't even eat rice that often.
Give me potatoes.
That's my sustenance.
I can live with that.
Potatoes and...
Spaghetti.
Or pasta.
Bread is just too good, man.
With no bread, you couldn't have pizzas.
You couldn't have your morning toast with cheese.
You couldn't have freaking...
The Danish lunch.
But I guess that's something specific to me.
But the classic rye bread.
You know, I couldn't even have that.
No way.
Definitely...
Rises out.
If you don't start soon, I'm not gonna fall asleep.
Wait.
Are you saying my gameplay is boring you to sleep?
I mean, I...
Fair?
I'm just messing around.
Bruschetta is my death row meal.
Oh, that's so good though.
I can get behind that.
Yeah, I know you didn't mean anything, uh...
Bad.
I'm just messing.
Actually, Jen, I may use that for the title of this video.
And we're gonna do it fully ASMR.
Nah, I think people would get pissed off if I did that.
If I did a whole episode with, like, an ASMR voice, people would go fucking furious, I think.
Also, I don't really know if I want to.
No ASMR, please?
Exactly, see?
I need to, like, code up some kind of randomized panner for the audio.
So whatever I speak, it just randomly goes in one ear only and the other.
A bunch of sine functions stacked on top of each other, you know?
And just have it be a super random feeling.
There we go.
Don't even have to do anything.
It happens automatically.
Ear-to-ear Minecraft.
Ten hours of silence, occasionally interrupted by Oliver Amnesia the War Bunker.
God, man.
I can't believe I screamed that much during Amnesia.
And how did nobody report me at that time for that?
I don't understand.
Like, how was I able to do that?
But I couldn't play an hour of Five Nights at Freddy's.
Hello?
What's wrong with people?
I guess it's my new neighbors.
I actually have such fond memories of the bunker now.
Even though it was literal hell for me to get through at times.
It really left a mark on me, you know?
I'll never forget it.
It's a different kind of horror.
Like, being chased constantly is a horrible feeling.
I actually did play Grounded Ashley.
With a friend of mine.
But we didn't get very far.
Because I saw giant ass spiders and I noped the fuck out of there.
But what I saw of the game was pretty good.
It seemed super polished and the idea was cool.
And I know there's like a mod or a setting to remove the spiders or something.
Maybe I'll do that in the future and check it out again.
That was just too much for me.
It was basically like...
You know in Elden Ring there were these ants?
I freaking hated those ants.
This was way worse than that.
Like, those spiders looked so convincing.
And they were so disgusting and...
Well, they were spiders.
I hate spiders.
Ugh.
Absolutely not.
I feel like you're enjoying KSP more than Freddy's.
Oh my god.
You're right.
I mean, is it really a surprise?
Freaking...
Five nights of Freddy's.
Nearly got me banned from my house.
And...
Nah, not really.
But...
You know, I had nightmares about that.
And I was screaming.
And it didn't sound like I was having a good time.
Whereas in KSP...
I literally can't stop playing it, you know?
That game is fantastic.
If you haven't played Kerbal Space Program yet.
And you're at all, like, even slightly interested in...
Space or, you know...
Um...
Rockets and stuff like that.
Definitely play it.
It is so fun.
I can't say good enough things about it.
Your KSP playthrough is always impressing me.
Really?
That's good.
People usually tell me that...
That my gameplay makes them mad.
Because of how bad it is.
So this is like the one game where I'm collecting W's, you know?
There's a lot of people in the YouTube comments on other games I play.
That are mad.
Because I'm so bad at the game.
But you know, I...
As long as I'm having fun, right?
This is the one game I'm really good at, it seems.
I also think the more fun you have with the game, the naturally better you are at it, you know?
Not that there's always a, you know, correspondence there or a one-to-one correlation.
Okay, man, it's time for some Minecraft, shall we?
I'm actually so weirdly excited for Minecraft right now.
I had...
You know how you get this weird craving for a specific food once in a while?
Like, for me, it'll be donuts, you know?
I will not be thinking about donuts for a month, and then one day...
Holy shit, I need donuts.
That's how I feel about Minecraft right now, this morning.
This early.
Okay.
Here we go, here we go.
You know what I love about this song?
You can actually hear...
The piano...
What do you call it?
Buttons?
Or...
Keys?
Yeah, keys.
Buttons.
Being pressed, you know?
Like, it's kind of a raw recording.
It's kind of cool.
It's nice.
Nice.
Okay.
The Owen Wilson edition.
The New Dawn.
I actually really like that name I gave this world.
Hot damn.
Let's see what I got up to last time.
Oh...
Guys.
So, I...
I went back...
And I watched that clip of me not noticing the fire, like, three times.
I...
And I...
Still cannot believe...
How the fuck I did not see it...
Hear it...
Or notice it.
This is probably the funniest fucking moment for me.
Like, in hindsight, looking back at what I've done.
It is so funny.
How...
And it went on forever as well.
Like...
I don't understand how I missed that.
It's crazy, man.
I mean...
Okay, I...
I will...
I'm never beating the blind allegations, you know?
After that incident.
It's over for me.
There's nothing I can do.
Oh my god.
Give me that.
Wait.
Did I need to pick that up?
What was I doing?
Oh my god.
Is it just me or is the game...
Insanely loud?
Test, test, test.
Hold on.
Rotund.
Is the game too loud?
Or was it okay?
Because I haven't changed anything.
Normal, okay.
Chests are a bit loud.
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess.
Are they always this loud?
That's crazy.
Did I change something?
I don't think so.
Eh.
We can maybe do this.
Probably not even gonna do anything.
Perceived loudness is a weird concept, man.
Oh, I remember now.
I...
Oh, this is such a good thing I did.
Remember?
So I put in...
Oh, this...
Oh, man.
We put this in here and that's gonna be turned into...
Frickin' iron of all things.
That is nuts.
Give me these.
Oh, yeah.
I mean, it's not a lot, but it's like...
It's passive income.
It's so good.
Put this in there.
I don't know what I was doing with this last time.
Observers.
Oh, I remember!
I was making...
Sugarcane farm.
Let's actually do that.
Wait, was it sugarcane?
What did I make?
Must have been sugarcane.
Yeah, yeah, sugarcane.
For sure.
Definitely.
What did I just put away?
Probably need that.
So we...
Oh, we need pistons for that.
Right.
Cobblestone, iron, and planks.
Wait, did we just get those iron nuggets?
They should be coming in here.
You saw that?
Or was that there before?
Maybe it was there before.
Wait, is it working?
Um...
I guess I won't be able to tell because I hid it.
I mean, it was working last time, so...
In fact, we're gonna put in more cobblestone.
Bro, the game feels...
Very loud.
Maybe it's because my perceived hearing is different in the morning.
Maybe it's just... I don't know.
Oh, by the way, something else.
I need to double check something.
I need to make sure that I don't fuck this up again.
Because last time we had frame pacing issues.
And... let me just check there.
Okay.
Should be okay.
Guys, how does the stream look right now?
Like, was it like...
Did it feel off with the pacing?
Because last time I asked you guys, you said, everything's good, it's fine, it works.
Then I checked the frickin' VOD.
And it looks like ass.
I don't know if I can trust you anymore.
Looks fine.
Wait.
Now watch, okay?
I'm walking around.
This should be smooth.
On my OBS preview, this looks like pure ass.
Okay, let me see.
Okay.
It's kinda blurry.
Yeah, but that's Twitch.
I mean, I'm moving around a lot in Minecraft.
That's always gonna produce...
some blurriness.
Some smearing or whatever it's called.
Okay, well...
Alright.
I will trust it.
So the problem I had last time was that I was...
for some reason, I had the FPS set to 120.
So it was actually recording 120 frames per second.
And then it was only sending 60 of those to Twitch.
And my computer cannot handle recording at 120 in 4K while streaming and doing the encoding work for that.
So it was dropping frames, you know?
It was very inconsistent, so it looked like ass.
But now it is set to 60, so it should be fine.
Okay.
I don't know why I made these, but I'm gonna take them.
Dude, I wouldn't mind living in this Minecraft world right here.
I think it's cozy.
Like, you would have access to cookies 24-7.
You know, you have these nice wheels spinning.
That always makes me happy.
Now, the only thing that would suck is, of course, the zombies.
Minus the creepy enemies, I would be totally cool with this.
Also, still no more iron, but I'm gonna go grab the...
Oh, this is why I came out here.
There we go.
That's a lot of cobblestone.
Okay.
And that should all be turned into iron and...
uh... flint.
That is such a cool setup, by the way.
Now, imagine we can now somehow create cobblestone.
Hmm.
Because if we can do that, it's essentially...
I mean, that's like saying...
Now, imagine we could just create iron, you know?
I mean, yeah.
But, uh, whatever.
Copper sheets.
Put them in here.
So, we have observers now.
We needed pistons.
And for that, we needed the...
Oh, shit.
That's why I needed cobblestone.
Redstone.
Oh, fuck.
Rescue it from the thingy.
Before it eats it all.
No!
Ah!
There's no way.
You actually gotta be kidding me.
I have no cobblestone left?
I really put it all in there?
Ah, here we go, here we go.
That should suffice.
Actually, no.
It's surprising how much you need for this.
And then we need a redstone and...
Uh, so redstone.
Cobblestone.
Iron.
That we have.
What was the last one?
Oh, planks.
Right.
Oh, and these are over here now, I believe.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
P-stone.
I'm gonna make eight.
So we match the amount of observers.
And let me think.
I'm trying to remember how I did this.
But it's pretty simple, really.
So you have the two...
Yeah, I'll figure it out.
Also, we need to plant this first, obviously.
So we gotta go find some...
Oh wait, that's bamboo.
I always get those mixed up.
How about we go feed the cows?
Wait, I'm level zero?
Or what happened there?
We're gonna get experience for this.
Dude, there's so many animals in here.
Whoa!
I feel like living conditions are not optimal anymore.
This is actually kinda bad for the animals.
Let me go collect experience.
Wait, are they pooping out experience when they have a baby?
So you gotta wait for them to actually...
You know...
Shoot out a baby.
And then the experience comes with it.
Move away, move away, move away.
Holy shit, they're so loud.
I just wanna murder them all.
I mean...
I mean, I do.
I wanna murder them.
Now, we had the fire incident last time.
I fixed it.
I'm so glad I did.
You can't even tell something happened here.
This one's even back.
I love those.
Okay.
Now...
Wait, I actually had an idea.
Check it out.
What if...
We made the floor...
Out of obsidian.
Where the animals are.
Okay.
The entire floor is obsidian.
Then we have this sort of launcher.
We launch TNT in there.
It blows everything up.
Except obsidian.
Everyone dies.
And it's super efficient.
But of course we would need to find a way to...
Create TNT.
In an efficient manner.
And hold on.
Gunpowder.
Can come from cinder flower.
And this is pretty easily obtainable, I think.
It comes from netherrack!
Wow.
You can even make glowstone dust by...
Okay, so whatever you put on this is gonna...
Wow.
Ha!
You can make redstone dust?
With a potion of strength.
Okay.
Man, there's so many cool combinations here.
Let's go to bed.
Man, I'm...
I'm really digging create.
I have to say that.
Like, it's adding a lot of really cool things.
Um...
Anyway, so we have these two now.
I guess we can throw the rest of the co...
No.
I'm actually gonna keep the rest of the cobblestone.
It's good to have some on hand, you know?
Yeah.
Let's see here.
Brother!
There's no iron in here!
Something is wrong with the machine!
Uh-oh.
Oh no, what's wrong with it?
Oh, shit.
Okay, that's...
That's fine.
Okay, so wait.
This is okay.
So out here something's going wrong.
I guess that would be...
Is it...
Oh, there's dirt down there!
That's probably what's...
Messing it up, because it doesn't allow dirt to go in.
But how did that end up there?
Ah, I think we fixed it.
Let's see now.
We should be getting iron.
We have six iron nuggets.
Let's see.
Come on, iron!
There could be other things getting clogged up between this chest and the washing mechanism.
I was in the washing mechanism yesterday evening.
It was great.
Very refreshing.
Come on.
Actually, we should look for flint and iron.
Is it because it's not updating live?
There's no way.
Oh, there it comes!
It is working, it's working.
It's just kinda slow, isn't it?
I actually don't like this here that I have.
It's too slow.
Like, I would love it to deposit one full stack at a time.
So this is something we have to change.
Um...
What is that?
Oh, it's the...
Shoot, okay.
Mmm...
Yeah.
I'm actually not gonna have this.
For now, we're gonna manually throw things in there.
Like here.
We're just gonna throw it in.
It's gonna be better.
I got some gravel too.
There you go.
Oh, but wait, uh...
Messing up gravel is gonna...
Do other things, isn't it?
I don't know.
Uh, anyway.
Okay, let's continue with this that I was doing.
Jesus.
We need to go find some sugar cane.
Oh, we also have this guy in here that we need to adopt.
I'm gonna take him in as my own.
Come on.
Tell me there's some...
Oh, I see some.
Gah!
I need a boat.
I should have thought of that.
Unless there's something in range.
What's going on here?
Maybe we had a little forest fire.
Mini forest fire.
Mmm...
Boat is over here.
I think it's time that we also start enhancing our estate today.
A couple more stone paths.
Making it look nicer.
Connecting things to the factory, perhaps.
I would love to add more to that stuff.
I also have to remember exactly how sugar cane grows.
It needs to be near water, but I'm not sure whether or not it needs to be in sand.
Or...
Dirt.
This probably sounds really dumb to someone who knows about sugar cane.
I don't!
Oh, it looks like it's growing on...
Grass.
That's good.
There's actually some over there.
Oh, wait!
That's growing on sand!
It's growing on both.
Hmm.
What the...
My game just minimized.
Great.
Thank you, game.
That was weird.
Anyway...
How do we have a digging machine?
Ooh!
I also have to experiment more with the...
Kinematic inverter, or whatever it's called.
The one that turns entire things into physical simulated objects.
Imagine I can cut this mountain off at the bottom...
And drag it out into the ocean.
You know?
Instead of mining it all away.
Because this is a thorn in my eye.
Whenever I see this right here, it makes my eyes bleed.
I hate it.
Wait, this should be enough.
Go back.
And of course, we also have to, uh...
Kidnap a hotel.
Oh, we gotta find one first.
It's actually kinda nuts that I still haven't found one of those...
In this world.
Usually I find them.
You know, in my worlds.
But this time around, not so much.
It's been difficult.
Let's wait.
You know what, actually?
I'm going to increase my...
Simulation distance.
32.
Apply.
Let's see if it melts my computer.
Alright.
Feels good.
Ta-da!
Yeah, okay.
Sounded a bit like a clicker.
From The Last of Us.
Is it slaughter time?
I could go murder a bunch of cows.
And you know what?
Killing cows also grants experience.
So it's like double dipping on the experience.
Okay, I'm trying to think what else I need.
So...
Oh, we need hoppers, of course.
To collect the stuff.
But I guess, um...
No.
We just need funnels, really.
That's even better.
Funnels, funnels, funnels...
Or no, not funnels.
Shoots.
But I guess we can bring some funnels too.
Oh, I have one shoot here.
Ten shoots!
Beautiful!
It's actually...
Almost perfect.
So we're gonna bring all those down to a...
A, um... belt.
This is like the new innovation, you know?
Compared to the one I had in...
My old world.
We bring them along.
And we deposit them...
Somewhere.
I would love for this...
I wonder if this can grow underground.
I do wonder if this needs sunlight to grow.
Oh wait, are we backed up again?
Let me...
Let me wait a sec here.
I need to see.
No!
It's going, it's going.
I need to cover this up though.
So things don't fall down and ruin it.
Okay.
The question is, where do we put it?
Hmm.
I'm gonna create a little experiment.
Right here.
I need to test whether or not this can grow underground.
Uh, we would need water for that.
Because if...
All of this can grow underground.
I mean, maybe it needs sunlight.
Think about it.
But it is Minecraft, right?
So...
Who knows?
Wait, I have a better idea.
Why don't I just do this?
And then we encase it in dirt and see what happens.
Um...
Make it a bit bigger, just in case.
Maybe there's some kind of limitation where it can't grow close to something.
I don't know if that's a thing.
Okay, we'll come back and check on that.
Soonish.
And if that grows in there, then we have confirmed that we can hide the entire thing underground.
But for now, I think I'll just try and remember what the actual design was.
Because that's kind of important.
So obviously we have an observer.
It's gonna look that way.
It's gonna be like, hmmm, what's happening?
Actually, no.
It just needs to be higher up.
So we have the piston.
I wonder if I can rotate this.
Only create components.
The other way.
So as soon as this...
See something goes...
I see something growing.
Destroy it.
Right?
Oh god, these guys are annoying me.
I really need to fix that soon.
Now...
This needs to send a signal to that.
When it happens.
And the way we did that...
God, I need to try and remember how the hell...
I haven't done redstone in a while.
Um...
Let me just confirm something.
So if I do this...
Yeah, it turns on.
Good.
Let's do...
Dirt.
Let's be naive.
See what happens now.
Aha!
Well, there it is.
Boom.
Fixed.
Wonderful.
The question is though, if we have two of these bad boys...
This is gonna connect these lines though, which is...
Maybe okay, actually.
Actually it's not, because then one is gonna...
They're gonna destroy each other.
So really, I think we need a repeater?
I think that's what we need here.
Hey, we have it.
Nice.
Actually, don't put the bow in there.
I will forget it.
This is like me putting my phone in my fridge when I grab something from it.
You know, where the...
Oh wait, my bow is here.
Never mind.
I thought I put my bow in there.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's see if this works.
Maybe that didn't count.
Doesn't work.
Okay.
Hmm.
I guess we can separate them by one.
It's not really a...
big deal.
But it would be nice to put them right next to each other.
Dude, I totally forgot how I did this shit.
Maybe I need to just turn them around.
It does turn on.
It turns on.
Um...
Oh god.
So when we have this...
Oh my god.
I have totally forgotten how to do this, man.
I used to be pretty good at this.
But that was also...
Remember when I made this back in the old world?
I, um...
I was also really into it at the time.
You know, I was creating machines left and right, so I had it all fresh in my mind.
So this is...
It's producing a signal, right?
We wanna bring it one down.
There's probably something from create we can use that's gonna make it easier, but...
I'm just trying to remember...
If we can do something with just these things here.
We also have tor...
Torches were a big deal, actually.
Remember, you could also power a block.
So if we power a block here...
That's gonna affect the neighboring one.
Ah, wait a sec.
Hold on.
If I do that...
I wonder if that's gonna power this block.
Wait, did it work?
Hey!
No.
Didn't work.
Okay, you know what?
I'm losing my...
Also, I can't do it here.
I can't listen to these assholes scream and yell all night.
It's gonna drive me crazy.
Close the door.
Go to sleep.
We do this someplace else.
Let's go over here instead.
Hey, look, we already have sort of a...
Set up for this.
Nah.
Yeah.
And then...
I mean, I'm pretty sure this is...
Oh, wait, maybe I put it one higher or something.
Oh, wait, it's the wrong way.
Whoops.
I mean, okay, we...
Let's just make a space in between.
It's not really a big deal.
Eh, whatever.
Or we just use a similar setup as there.
Oh my god, wait a minute.
What am I doing?
I could just plant...
I could just plant it right here if I needed to.
Like, I could put it right there if I...
But it's not gonna be a lot, right?
Yeah.
But then we would have to do all that again.
It's also kinda...
Weird.
Also, let's go check if the sugar cane has grown.
Because then we know whether or not we can do it on the ground.
And surely by now it should have grown, right?
Okay, shit.
Maybe it doesn't.
Ah.
Okay, let's just try and make another one of these up there.
I guess it's easier.
We can, you know, sweep out a bigger surface area quickly with that.
And it costs less components.
Okay, so for that, we're gonna need a...
We don't technically need a windmill.
We can use something else.
We can use a...
Oh, since we're going to be near the water and doing it, let's use a water wheel.
I think I have that.
Somewhere.
Oh, I used them, I think.
Uh, yeah.
I used them.
What does it take?
Let's make a large water wheel.
So we need a water wheel first.
So shaft.
Large one.
And then I generally just want more shafts.
And that's gonna cost...
Ooh, look at all this.
Wait, we're actually full here.
That ain't good.
Oh, shit.
Not ideal.
It's not ideal, but okay.
Whatever.
Put them in there.
We're gonna get so much flint.
This belongs over here.
Wait, I forgot we had elytra!
Oh my god, we should be flying everywhere.
Huh.
Nice.
Funnel.
Uh, we don't need this anymore because we're not doing that.
Right, so for...
Oops.
For shafts, we needed the...
Not that one.
The other one.
Ah.
Don't tell me it can't make it.
Oh no.
No, no.
Do I have andesite?
Man, I'm really always short on that, huh?
Now, there is a way.
There's a pathway here.
Andesite.
I think we should start making that as well so we can get this more...
Yeah, look at this.
Right, that's what I wanted to do last time.
So we already have a lot of gravel coming out of the crushing wheel.
And some of that gravel is gonna be used to create iron.
We're gonna, you know, split off some of the gravel to become andesite.
Because we have so much flint.
That's sick.
Let's work on that now.
Before we do the sugarcane thing.
Because I'm feeling it.
Okay.
So, that would be right about...
Here.
So, let's say right before...
So, we need a tunnel for this.
Not a funnel, but a tunnel.
Maybe I'll take this with me too.
Oh, andesite alloy!
Do I have more of that?
Just hanging about?
Okay.
So, I'm trying to think what else I would need for this.
Um...
We needed the press...
Which I don't think I just have.
I need to make a new one.
I'm pretty sure they needed a iron...
block.
Yeah.
Iron block and a side casing and shaft.
There we go.
We got that.
And I think it was a...
basin that we needed as well.
Yeah.
But the thing is...
Wait, hold on.
I wonder if we can put this on...
a belt instead.
Oh wait, there's also this combination here.
Diorite can be gotten from...
What?
Really?
Cobblestone and nether quartz.
Okay.
Yeah.
But, okay.
So, I guess we could do it that way.
But I don't want to do it that way.
Unless calcite...
Calcite...
Nah.
Okay.
We're gonna stick to the original plan here.
I'm just trying to think how we would do this.
So, we split off half of the gravel...
and we take all of...
or maybe some of the flint.
Let's say they come in on separate belts.
They meet...
and they meet on one belt.
They all go together...
and they reach this processing of being compacted, right?
But it seems to me like we need a basin for that.
So, they all fall into the basin.
They get compacted.
And then we need to extract from the basin when it's done.
Which means we need a filter...
that only takes the output ingredients before it allows it to flow out.
And we already have something similar happening over here...
near the factory.
I need to see this again.
Yeah.
But here we don't compact, we mix.
Right?
So, it goes in here.
Oh, that's right!
It even has this little...
output thingy there.
Oh, that's super convenient.
Yeah.
It goes in there...
comes out...
and then we should have...
and the site.
It's that simple.
Our things...
I like just...
what is being thrown here?
This is just happening constantly.
I love it.
Let's go build it.
I think I have the whole thing...
planned out in my head now.
It's gonna work...
very nicely.
The only thing we need to think about is...
how to split the items perfectly.
And I think we needed a brass tunnel for that.
Did I not make those?
Brass tunnel...
Oh!
We got them!
Sweet!
I need to ponder that actually.
We can...
Yeah, we can also cover up the belts with them...
if we wanted to...
to make it look nice.
Filter slots!
So now they come in.
Filters on inbound item connections...
What did you say?
Simply block non-matching items.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Filters on outbound connections can be used to sort items by type.
Yes.
But...
How can we...
Whenever a passing item has multiple valid exits...
the distribution mode will decide how to handle it.
So right now there's no filter, so they...
I guess they just get split in half.
Would be my guess.
Half and half.
That's a little too strong for me usually, but...
Brass tunnels on parallel belts will form a group.
No way!
So you put like a billion items on this belt and it just gets sorted?
Whoa!
That's crazy.
Wait, what is that?
Oh, that's part of the belt.
Okay.
Wow.
It's like the airport system, you know?
For this, items can also be inserted into the tunnel block directly.
Okay.
Oh, so...
Oh, that's cool!
So even if you put this in here, it's still gonna come out there.
Oh my god.
Wow.
I guess it's just another input mode on top.
It's like this one over here, but on top.
It has the same function.
Distribution modes.
The distribution behavior of brass tunnels can be configured.
Righto.
Maybe you can set it to half and half or something.
Split will attempt to distribute the stack evenly.
Okay.
Makes sense.
If an output is unable to take more items, it will be skipped.
Forced split will never skip outputs and instead wait until they are free.
Ah!
Okay.
I see.
So only if everything can flow, it lets it flow.
Round robin keeps stacks whole and cycles through outputs iteratively.
Oh!
Okay, so...
With the assigned stack size?
This is crazy.
There's so much to this.
Once again, if an output is unable to take more items, it will be skipped.
Then there's that one.
Forced round robin never skips outputs.
Oh my god.
Prefer nearest prioritizes the outputs closest to the item's input location.
Oh my goodness.
Randomize will distribute whole stacks to randomly picked outputs.
Jesus Christ, brother.
The tunnels are insane.
Now, I still need shafts.
We can make a couple here.
Well, that should be enough actually.
We don't need that many.
Now we have brass tunnels.
We got funnels.
And let me try and see what else we need.
So it comes in, it gets split.
It's on the belt.
Oh, we are definitely gonna need some wheels.
I think I have those.
And we probably also should take some...
What are they called?
The thingies...
Is it gear shift?
It's the one with the...
Horizontalism.
Oh!
Also, we need uppers and downers.
But that's a given.
You always want that.
Did I really distribute them randomly?
Like an idiot?
Come on, man.
Oh my god, I have 64 shafts.
This is what I mean, like, I need to keep track of this.
This is crazy.
So what is the andesite tunnel and how...
Why am I not just using that?
Cover up belts.
Oh, it still does it.
Well, there you go.
I guess we don't even need a brass tunnel down there on one of them.
Let's wait.
Okay.
Makes it cheaper.
Now that we have that...
What else do we need?
So...
We probably need...
We can turn half of these into the vertical ones.
Like that.
Just to have it.
Let's put them up in the corner.
Uppers and downers.
Now I needed the...
What are they called?
The...
Belt...
No, it's the...
Chain drive.
That one.
I love these.
It's just iron nuggets.
Oh my goodness.
Guess what I have a lot of.
Oh my god, they're cheap to make.
Wow.
That's crazy.
We probably also need a new source of power soon.
Because I feel like we're running low on...
Power here.
Okay.
So the gravel needs to be split off before.
So right here, I guess.
We could also go that way.
Wait, which way should I go?
I think it would be cooler to go that way.
Really make it...
Oh my god, what's happening?
My game just minimized again.
Stop that.
Jesus.
Basically, I'm thinking of...
So something I used to do when I was playing...
Um...
What's that game called?
Theme Park Simulator...
No, Rollercoaster Tycoon.
You know the first one?
I used to love making spaghetti rides.
You know, I would just merge everything everywhere and have it be going in and out.
And just be complete mess, you know?
I love that.
But...
That's what I'm trying to go for here.
I actually really do love that.
Okay, so this path is not great.
The more compact, the cooler, in my opinion, you know?
Okay, so I guess we can go that way instead.
Yeah!
Oh my god.
There we go.
The problem is there's water here.
So maybe we...
Ah!
Even better idea.
We're gonna go...
Further back this way.
Oh my god.
Right here.
Yeah!
Oh my goodness.
Then we come out here.
Oh no!
Why you gotta be like that?
This is already looking crazy in here, isn't it?
I mean, look at it!
Tell me this isn't cool as hell.
I think it is.
I need some lights.
Uh...
We could go even further back.
I mean, we can split them off quite early, I guess.
We could even do it...
here.
The rest goes...
that way, maybe?
Or...
Hold on.
So, here's where...
Also...
Isn't this a complete waste of...
No, actually, this is fine.
But I guess, you know, a tunnel could be used here to great effect.
But I already put this down.
This is working fine.
It's okay.
Let's split it off over here.
Oh!
I don't need this to be on the belt.
This is actually...
I'll clean it up later.
So!
We have all the gravel coming out here.
Just to double check.
And the sides.
It's gravel and two flint.
Oh, and lava.
Wait, I wonder if I need to supply...
more and more lava.
Or if one...
piece of lava will work.
Oh, shit.
Maybe I actually need to somehow...
have more lava.
Wait, how the...
hell?
Wait a minute.
Oh, no.
This is actually kind of ruining everything.
We need to perform a test.
Basin.
Don't have it.
I must...
There we go.
We got one.
Um...
Let me just do it here.
For now.
Oh, my God!
There's lava down there.
Maybe it's fine.
Okay, so...
Apparently, if we put lava in here now...
I'm gonna grab the lava from here if I have it.
Ah, shit.
Let's go grab some.
My...
problem right now is...
if we do need to supply lava again and again and again...
then we're in big trouble.
because...
that's...
that's not something that will just keep going.
Like, you need to constantly go find lava then.
Unless we can find a way to infinitely make lava.
And I have no idea how we would even go about doing that.
Because now we have lava.
Let's try this.
I need gravel...
and flint.
I got them both.
Gravel...
and flint.
Ooh!
Compactification!
No!
It's using lava!
Lava!
Aww!
My dreams are gone.
I thought it would just be like one lava and that's it.
Dang it.
That's really bad.
Just gotta clean up my inventory slightly here.
It's kind of annoying.
Ah, sugar cane, we can put that here for now.
You know what I should do, really?
Since I'm going around...
uh...
doing other things right now, I may as well put this up here right now, right?
Ah, shit!
Never mind.
This needs to be lower then.
Oh my god, okay.
It's not actually that simple.
For some reason, I expected it to just be as smart.
You know?
And do it...
when it grows accordingly.
Oh well.
Wait, did I just lose half...
Where did my sugar cane go?
Oh, it got picked up probably.
Oh yeah, okay.
So it should be in the chest.
Yep.
Nice.
We'll have to think about that some more.
Okay.
So how do we solve this problem with the lava?
Uh...
Let's try and figure out a way to...
get a lot of lava, huh?
So, the way I'm thinking...
Maybe it just magically works.
Like, we could try to put a pipe into some lava.
And see that when we suck the lava, is it gonna, you know...
actually get sucked?
Or is it like being a continuous suck?
You know what I mean?
Probably not.
I'll show you what I mean.
But we do need pipes.
And...
We could do a fluid tank.
Pump would be nice too.
And you know what?
I wanna bring my little...
engine that could.
And then we need also fuel for that.
Which I have.
And I think that's about it.
Right.
Let's go pump out some lava over here.
Near the lava...
location.
Wait.
Guys, I have an idea how we can get infinite lava.
We just suck the nether dry of lava.
We bring a pipe from the underworld...
all the way to here, and we just...
suck the resources out of that place.
I don't know if we can actually go through a portal with it though.
Wait, maybe we can.
Because...
apparently you can go through that with a train, right?
So why... maybe the same logic applies to other things in Create.
But let's try this first.
Wait, this looks really weird.
I would assume we would probably need to do this from a source block.
But that's not how lava works, is it?
Or maybe it is.
Oh shit, it burned.
Wait, it burned there, but not...
Wait, this is weird.
Oh, it's just gonna replace the lava, of course.
Oh, I know what we need.
We need a drain.
Maybe we can put a drain underneath the lava, and it'll...
continuously suck.
Drain.
I got it.
Oh wait, it's an item drain though.
This is...
Oh, actually what this means is you put like a...
bottle on there, and then it'll drain the bottle.
It's not gonna...
Oh no.
Wait, I have a different idea.
Let's try this instead.
Maybe if you put lava inside a...
fluid...
No.
For sure not, right?
Large amounts of fluid.
I'm...
I'm like so confused why this...
So, with water, you can put the pipe inside the water, and it'll suck it out, right?
Maybe...
Maybe you need to...
Oh, that's funny.
Maybe we do it like that?
It's not gonna work, is it?
Let's try it.
Yeah, that's good.
Beautiful.
And then let's put a little container here.
I just need to put in some...
fuel.
Yeah, I didn't expect this to work.
But let's try to do this now.
Okay, but check.
This lava is flowing, right?
What if I take lava from here...
and put it there?
Why is it, like, not flat?
It's flowing, and I don't like that.
Oh, also, this is not even the right way.
Still nothing?
You're kidding me.
Wait, what?
What happened to my pipe?
Oh, stop, stop, stop.
Put in a bit more.
Okay, hold on.
We're gonna try something.
Because this is flowing, right?
I'm gonna try and bring it to that.
Oh, lava!
It's working, it's working!
Okay!
For the question though, is it infinite?
How come it's not filling up more?
Alright, see, now it works again.
Okay, so it sucks in a certain amount, then it stops.
That is interesting.
You can see it moving.
Yeah, now we get more.
Okay.
Well, the problem with this...
is that...
we can't just put a pipe near some lava and expect it to just keep working.
Unless...
Let's say you have multiple levels of lava.
And you...
plug in the pipe underneath.
So that everything flows down to it.
Right?
Uh, you know what?
Let's actually go to the nether and check this, because that's the obvious place to check this.
Nah, this is probably...
rip the pipe.
Ah, some of it.
Whatever.
I got everything I needed.
I even have a golden helmet.
Whee!
Nether time.
God, it feels incredible flying again.
It's been a minute, huh?
Okay, so...
I actually just got an idea.
We have multiple experiments we can...
run.
Wait, what the...
Oh, I did some, uh...
I did some funky business here last time.
That iron nugget, I kinda want that.
Ah, you know what?
I'll drink this too.
Bottoms up.
Just to get rid of it.
So...
Water that's flowing down like that.
See, that's interesting.
Oh god, my inventory is absolutely...
How am I just running out of space?
I...
I gotta go back.
I gotta fix this before I...
I...
I can't handle it otherwise.
I'm going to lose my mind.
I'm gonna clean up the inventory.
I'm... I'm...
You know what?
Every time I approach this house, I'm not liking it.
This portion is unfinished!
That's why I don't like it.
Look, we need a little, uh...
uh...
thingy here to...
top it off.
That's what's been missing there.
Let's put that there.
We don't need that right now.
We don't need these right now.
Or that.
Or this.
I'm trying to put all the important things in the bottom right of these chests, so I won't forget them again.
Yeah, this can wait, because we don't need that right now.
There we go.
Gravel.
Much better.
There.
So all we need is pipe.
That.
Okay.
I wonder if you can make a windmill...
inside the nether.
Is there even wind...
in the nether?
There's definitely air, otherwise I wouldn't be able to fly in there.
Asking the real questions.
Suck it!
Thank you.
Okay, so two experiments we're gonna run.
One is try and suck it from this.
I doubt it's gonna work.
Because I think we have established that we need a fresh source of lava.
But let's try it anyway.
Who knows?
Oh, I need to rotate this guy.
I mean, that...
kinda looks cool.
Fuck!
I forgot the cock.
I hate that.
And now, especially when the music just started, man.
Aww, what a bummer.
Gimme that.
What else do I need?
So we put the thing in, we put that in.
Then we have the thing, and we put the...
Oh!
Ha-ha!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Good thing I double-checked in my mind.
Coal we have now.
And then it goes in the thing, and it...
Okay.
Sounds good.
You know what?
I'm gonna bring more fire protection potions.
Because we are gonna be playing with fire.
I'll take that.
And that.
In fact, I'm gonna quickly brew them to be even better.
Potion of Harming.
No idea how I made that.
There you go, make them better.
Okay.
I'm gonna be going quite deep as well.
Wonderful.
Dude, this portal looks weird.
It's like weirdly too long.
It's like...
I'm not used to it.
I expected it to just be fatter.
I don't know why I'm suddenly having doubts about my portal shape.
There.
Oh, we also need to do this.
Alright.
You wanna fight?
We can fight.
This will not work.
Yeah.
I mean...
To be expected.
But at least we have it crossed off our list.
No big surprise there.
Let's go find a lot of lava.
There's a bunch of lava down there.
But it is kind of far down.
But I guess I can fly.
Man, this is actually kind of annoying.
Unless...
Wait, what if we were to make a portal...
Down below?
I'm pretty sure if we make a portal...
Right below that portal...
Near the lava...
It's going to link up to the same portal up above.
Genius.
I'm gonna do that.
Remember the portal experiments of 69?
Lot of pain and sweat went into that.
Now I need obsidian and I need a...
Little fire thingy.
Don't think six is enough.
Fire thingy there.
Okay.
Anything else I need?
Uh, yeah.
I need more...
Obsidian.
And this should be fast now...
Because I have a sick pickaxe.
That's so sick.
There should be enough...
How's it hanging?
Alrighty.
Back into the nether.
Let me also check this real quick.
Okay, guys.
Do you think...
The sugar cane has grown?
Yes or no?
I'm gonna say no.
Fuck!
Okay, it works!
Nevermind.
Dammit, man.
I mean, it's good.
It's good, it's good.
Just that I lost a bet.
Alright, now we know that.
So we could potentially put the thing on the ground...
If we wanna go for the observer route.
Okay, we got obsidian.
And we got fireworks.
Put that there.
So, you know what I'm gonna do?
Just to be absolutely sure about this.
I actually could be wrong about the portal mechanics here.
But I think I'm not wrong.
I think I'm pretty okay right.
I'm gonna dig straight down.
But like here.
Are you gonna mess with me?
You know what, I'm gonna put this on myself.
Just to be safe.
I mean, we should emerge near some lava.
Even though I have fire protection, I'm kinda scared.
I definitely understand the dangers of digging straight down.
Wait, how have we not hit lava?
Oh, here we go, here we go.
Okay.
So...
Um...
I guess I can just jump in the lava.
It's not really a big deal.
In fact, I'm gonna fly.
Okay.
And this is where we came down.
Right there.
Let's go to...
Right over here then.
Ow, ow, ow.
Imagine having your eyes in lava.
The ultimate LASIK operation.
Now I'm gonna show you my plan.
It's like this, okay?
Ah, you know what, I should probably do it.
Wait, can I just place them anywhere?
Oh my god!
But...
Wait, I need to get...
Further over here.
How much time?
Four minutes.
Okay, dude.
This is so scary, actually.
We're gonna be sucking from the...
Bottom of the pit.
Right there, this is the suck.
Ho-ho!
Can I jump up on that?
Oh, I can indeed!
Oh, that's so sweet.
I have no idea exactly where I am, but that's okay.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
We may have a problem though.
Mmm!
What, wait, what am I doing?
I'm making a portal down here!
I'm not going up with this!
Uh...
Wait, hold on.
I'm an idiot.
Why am I even doing this?
I don't even know if I can do this.
Shit.
We need...
We need to make a basic experiment real fast here.
We can leave this...
Oh, it's burning when I...
Oh, that's bad.
I'm losing my pipes.
We need a really basic experiment.
Come on.
Get to land.
Okay, so...
Why am I so...
Slow?
Oh.
I don't understand why I'm so slow.
Stop being slow.
Am I burning...
Like...
I'm not in lava anymore, stop.
Like, this feels wrong.
No, that should be okay.
Check it out.
We're gonna...
That's good enough.
Pointing the right way.
How the hell am I gonna generate power in here?
Maybe just with a windmill.
We'll have to see if that works.
There's...
I feel like this is not gonna work.
No!
But maybe, maybe...
Hold on.
Oh...
Of course it's not gonna work.
What was I even thinking?
For some reason I just...
I don't know why I just assumed I could do this.
How does a...
Also, where the hell am I?
Wait, what?
Okay, never mind.
The portal experiments of 69...
Are definitely not...
Relevant.
Oh my god, we're over here.
Say what?
Okay then.
Also...
Oh wait, I can just do this.
Much better.
I was like, I'm gonna lose all that, but I'm not.
Well guys...
I mean, okay.
I could set up the whole operation in the nether.
Right?
That's one way to do it.
We set it all up in here.
And then we run the whole thing from here.
And so apparently trains can go through...
Fuck!
I wasn't touching!
I wasn't even touching it!
Okay.
Maybe we can...
I don't know...
Load up a train?
And send it...
Through?
Oh no, this sounds insanely complicated.
Wait, why am I even doing all this?
I forgot.
Why do I need lava?
Oh yeah, I was making andesite.
Ah...
Jesus.
Maybe there's a better way.
Wait, can I somehow...
Create lava?
Creating lava?
How do I create lava?
Let's say I were to make my own lava.
I guess you would need a lot of heat.
And stone.
Because it's molten stone, right?
Maybe you can blast it?
I mean, of course...
Oh yeah, obviously it's gonna do that.
How on earth would you keep getting lava?
I think it may just be a case of setting it all up in the nether.
The problem with that is...
It's not gonna simulate...
You know, unless I'm in there, which is horrible.
The idea is to have something that just goes while I'm at home.
So I think that plan is out of the window, actually.
Yeah, in fact, the nether is a terrible plan just because of that.
I didn't even think of that.
Yeah.
That already puts it to sleep, you know?
Frick.
Okay, maybe we have to resort to some other way.
We can make it with cobblestone and diorite.
And diorite can be made from calcite.
And maybe there's an easy way to get calcite?
I don't think there is.
We have to, like, find it.
I don't like that very much.
Hey, we can turn it back to cobblestone.
Yeah, okay.
I could just stop being a lazy bitch.
You know?
And get out there and start digging.
I mean, it's not the end of the world.
We have a crazy digging machine.
I think I'm trying to overdo it.
Really.
We really don't need to be that crazy.
Is that exotic?
No.
This is exotic.
That's not exotic.
Yeah, let's just go dig.
Let's have a nice digging session.
And this time, we're going to dig a little further down.
Put this stuff back.
There's so many cogwheels.
Besides, I need experience.
I need to repair my pickaxe and...
Okay, my elytra is doing pretty well, but, you know.
Oh, this is in here.
Spyglass.
That one there.
Little engine that could.
Oh, we bring coal, actually, for this.
Then we take this guy.
And emergency things to bring is, of course, the cart assembler.
A tiny handle.
That one.
And...
Then, of course, some rails.
That's pretty much it, I think.
Now, if only I could find a bunch of diorite.
Because if we can find cobblestone and diorite consistently...
Then we're cooking.
I'm going to bring my bed.
Am I?
I'm not.
But I am going to go slaughter some cows.
I really want to bring a sword for that, actually.
If I have it.
I got one.
Ah, it's fine.
I seem to remember having a better sword, but maybe I lost it.
Probably did.
Alright, cows and sheep.
The day has finally come.
You're all gonna die.
Oh wait, I shouldn't jump.
I should just do this.
Wait, what?
Oh, I unlocked some new wool.
It's a terrible sword.
Okay, I think that will do it.
Oh my god, how did you get in?
God, I hate this...
You know what?
Oh my god!
Wow.
Those bastards are loud.
63...
Oh my, that's perfect.
It's a stack.
Couldn't have gone better.
We have a blaster ready out here too, so I can just blast immediately.
Wait.
Yeah.
I should just...
Wait, no, no, wait, wait.
We want smoke.
We can't blast it.
Ah shit, whatever.
Just smoke it.
I guess for a smoker...
What would you need?
I...
Why am I blanking on this?
Oh, it's just a campfire, I think.
Yeah, I don't have that right now.
Dang.
We got leather though.
You what, mate?
Come on then.
Stealing my eggs.
I see.
Oh!
I hate that.
Because of you, this tree needs to die.
Congratulations.
Good job.
Stupid tree.
Remember what you've done here.
You did this.
You.
And all this wool too.
Put it in here.
Okay, are we ready?
Let's grab some steaks and head out.
That's good enough.
Time for some digging!
Gone digging.
And then we also have to figure out how to make that damn potion of weakness.
So we can...
Convert that villager.
And turn him into a good boy.
That's still kind of an annoying mystery.
Um...
How far down?
I mean, I see diorite there.
But I also don't want to turn my mountain right next to me into Swiss cheese.
So I think we should go a little further.
Find another mountain.
In fact, we're gonna turn it into a wonderful little digging session.
What about this mountain?
It's still kind of close.
Let's go really far.
I forgot a shield.
This could bite me in the ass.
Did I bring a...
Oh, I didn't even...
A smart man would head back right now.
You know what?
I'm a smart man.
I'm heading back.
I gotta get a shield.
I gotta get a compass.
Compass.
And...
Also a bed.
Shield, compass, bed, and a boat.
Yeah, let's not play this dumb.
God, the elytra is incredible, isn't it?
Look how...
What do you call it?
Slowly it's...
Durability is decreasing now.
And we haven't even gotten the full unbreaking.
It's just unbreaking too.
It can be better.
And then we also have this.
More meat.
Boat.
Maybe I'll bring even more torches too.
Because we're gonna be lighting.
Don't need the sword, actually.
Shield.
But do I make a new one?
Nah, this will...
This will be fine.
For my gear, I think we will need a...
Diamond helmet.
Yep.
And that's about it, I think.
Oh, bed.
Bed is good.
Bed boat.
I got the arrows.
Wonderful.
Oh, compass, compass.
And that's it.
Maybe some more of these.
47.
There we go.
So glad I went back.
Good stuff.
I actually don't mind going to the snowy biome over here.
Let's find a snowy mountain and just go down and start digging like crazy.
I wonder if the game is going to limit you.
Like, let's say I make a 100 by 100 digging machine and we just fucking plow through a mountain.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
I mean...
What's going to stop me from making it happen?
You know?
Just eradicate a mountain in one go.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
That's kind of cool looking over there.
I feel so safe with this compass.
It's going to lead me straight home.
It's like, uh...
Unheard...
Levels of...
Safety.
Unheard of levels of safety.
That's what I meant to say.
For me at least.
I feel so free and...
I don't know.
What's that?
What does it look like?
Oh, this is ice.
Oh, right.
Okay.
I see.
Look at that over there.
So many crimes here, I feel like.
Like, what is that even?
Ew.
Actually, we haven't been here before.
Look.
Everything's generating.
There's a whole new path.
Look at that tree!
It's a beautiful tree.
Ew, man.
What the fuck is this?
Knock run?
I'm gonna stay in the snowy biome.
Oh!
I also wanted to find a little, uh...
Uh...
Snow hut.
Is that it?
No way!
Show me the thing!
Oh no!
Why is there no thing?
Nice bed.
I can't believe I just found that right after saying it.
Now I wanna find more!
Let's look for them.
There's a tower over there.
You can go rob them real quick.
That sounds fun.
Just gonna fly up top, grab it and get out.
I'll take the iron, thank you very much.
You can have my snowballs.
And my snow carpet.
Or white carpet.
I don't really want anything else.
I'm good.
Let's scope the area.
Any snow huts?
Igloo!
That's what they're called.
Scanning, scanning.
That's a big mountain over there, look.
Ooh!
Guys, this is the mountain to dig inside.
We're gonna be digging in there.
Let's check it out.
We're gonna go down here.
This is the plan.
We're gonna take samples of the mountain.
And I love that I can just do that.
We're gonna do that!
I wonder how this is gonna work on ice.
It's probably fine.
Um...
Wait, I actually lose my coal.
There are certain situations where you lose the coal.
What's wrong?
Are you lacking rails?
Maybe.
Holy shit!
There you go.
Get on the rail!
There we go, it's going, it's going.
We're taking a sample out of the mountain.
Imagine having three digging machines.
And you take samples in each direction.
Ooh.
Possibilities.
I also need to see...
the drill.
Yeah, so we need a bunch of antisides to even make more drills too.
And iron.
But iron is a...
it's kinda automatic now.
In a way.
And I think after we've taken a sample of this mountain, we're gonna go a little deeper.
Maybe like 10 or 15 blocks deeper, and then we're gonna do the same thing.
Just to see what kind of stuff we're gonna get, you know?
But so far, this looks like pretty standard just cobblestone.
And, you know, a bit of sink and stuff like that.
Got some copper too.
Some iron here.
I'll take that.
And the good thing is, it's just gonna keep supplying itself with coal too, because it keeps finding coal.
Dude, this machine is actually so amazing.
It's completely self-sufficient.
The only times it doesn't work is when you hit...
lava?
But then, somehow it actually still works.
No, it doesn't actually, because as soon as this guy destroys the tracks behind it, the lava will flow again and it'll ruin things.
That's the only thing that it doesn't work well with.
Okay, I think we've taken a good enough sample here.
Thank you.
Come again.
Dead experience.
Now we're just gonna dig down.
I'm actually gonna do it here.
I was like, why am I not getting levels?
But it's my pickaxe!
Sucking it all up.
Okay.
Let's do it here.
We need a bit of space though.
Actually, maybe it makes more sense to keep digging until we find a cave.
And then we deployed there.
Otherwise, it's gonna take ages.
We gotta listen for creatures.
Keep your ears sharp.
Never understood the saying, keep your eyes peeled.
Peeling eyes sounds painful.
And how is that even relevant to, you know, keeping an eye out?
Now that I think about it, that saying is also weird.
Oh!
Oh my god!
Wow.
That's a big ol' cave.
So dark!
Oh, I need night vision, man.
Really do.
Let's go down here and start digging down there.
But we do need to kill these fools.
This bow is powerful now.
Oh my god.
So nice.
Bunch of iron here, actually.
Wait, what the hell is...
Have you ever seen this?
This is a giant Stalic Malachmatite.
All the way from the roof...
To the floor.
Wow!
Let's dig it!
Let's dig straight through that.
That's gonna be fun.
Uh...
Rails, right.
Put that there.
And then this should be okay...
Yeah...
Looks about right.
Now, I may need to do a little pre-rail like that.
Yeah, that's better.
Let's see what happens!
Let's see where we end up...
I'm so excited, actually.
I'm gonna dig this iron since I'm here.
Gotta take the iron, right?
Even though we have iron at home...
We want more iron.
And now that I have the simulation...
Distance...
Tuned all the way up...
This should be able to just, you know...
Do its thing.
No problem.
God, I love having a compass that points to home!
I feel so safe!
Like, it doesn't even matter where I go or what I do.
End side we keep, of course.
Same with diorite.
Cobblestone is less important, really.
There's new music?
I've not heard this track!
We got new music, boys!
I think it's from creative.
Has to be.
This is nice.
I guess it's kind of fitting that we have creative music...
When we're playing create.
Right?
Ah, give me some cobble.
Nah, I don't care about covering that up.
I don't give a shit.
I mean, I do, but I don't.
You know?
Am I hearing gravel?
I think I hear some gravel!
I feel like we've taken a pretty good sample here.
We could go even further down.
But let's keep digging.
I feel like maybe we're getting good stuff.
Let's see.
Whoops.
What have we gotten here?
Hey, a bunch of diorite!
Whoa!
Guys, I think andesite problem is solved!
You just go a little deeper and you get diorite en masse.
Oh, this is huge!
What else did I get?
Crimsight.
Wait, crimsight?
What can I use that for?
I don't know.
Maybe I didn't pick it up yet?
No, I did.
Getting iron too!
Nice!
This is a great digging session.
I do want to go even further down so that we can potentially even find diamonds as we dig.
Imagine that.
Are we entering another cave?
Perchance?
Let's...
Let's go deeper now.
And let's go this way now.
Yeah, this is a new track.
So loud, man.
It's a nice track though.
The problem is I can't hear the animals.
When they come out at night.
But...
I'm pretty far down now.
I may be hitting rock bottom here soon.
Oh!
There's no way!
Dude, look!
Oh yeah!
I actually love this.
I've been wanting to find this anyway.
For a while.
Uh...
This one...
I don't care about that.
But wait, hold on.
We actually have a problem maybe.
Dude, why don't I just...
raise the entire place?
Think about it.
I set the machine to work, right?
It raises through the entire place.
If it encounters chests, it's gonna destroy the chest.
And it'll pick up the contents.
Wait, is it?
I'm not sure it'll pick up chest contents.
But it's worth a try, I guess.
Basically, I just want to dig.
Like, I want to dig everything.
I want to dig the world.
I'm a little scared.
Going flying?
I'm pretty sure that actually alerts things down here.
Dude, we need cardboard.
This is the cardboard...
place.
Wait, what...
Look!
The frickin...
uh...
flitter motion is making sounds.
I don't know why I only remembered the German word for that.
Well, at least that means these are not connected to anything.
I'm just gonna...
Oh my god, it's...
massive!
Aha!
Achievement.
Can I zoom?
Wait, why are there ladders?
We need to find...
chests here.
Man, it's so dark...
Wait, there's torches over there.
I can't jump down there.
It's gonna make s...
Oh no.
I don't actually know if I want to be here.
It's...
I can't see shit.
I also don't have my blinds closed, so the sun is streaming in.
I can't see anything.
Oh yeah, I'm just gonna jump down over here.
Or I just fly.
Okay.
Fuck it.
Oh, that actually worked pretty well.
Okay, uh...
I feel like we should bookmark this place somehow.
And come back, you know, with night vision potions and stuff like that.
But I do want to find a couple chests since I'm here.
Where would they be?
And let's not forget, maybe grabbing some of this material in here...
will give me new create recipes.
God, it's so dark.
I think I'm just gonna dig.
Should we... should we try to raise the place?
This may be a terrible idea.
Let's have a little backup situation going over here.
Oh, but wait, I can't even escape them if...
Uh...
I mean, I have... I have elytra.
I can fly away.
It's okay.
Ha!
This may be a horrible idea!
You ready?
Dig!
Hey, what's happening?
Wait, oh, oh, do we not have...
No, you do have...
Oh, you... maybe you can't place it on this?
No...
Really?
No, you can, you can.
Why did you stop?
Maybe I need to reload this...
There you go.
Brother.
Go!
Go, go, go!
It's going, it's going, it's going, it's going.
If shit hits the fan, I'm...
ready to be out of here.
I'm scared to follow it.
I'm just gonna sit back and observe.
It stopped again!
Why did you stop?
It's probably a terrible idea!
It's definitely alerting.
It's going.
The thing I wonder though, like, let's say it does make sound and it triggers the guy to spawn.
Like, I'm not gonna have the aggro, it's gonna be my machine that has the aggro.
I'm really curious how that's gonna...
play out.
It's generating experience.
Because it's destroying this, I guess.
It's also sort of creating a path that I know is gonna be safe to walk on now, right?
Yeah.
I guess.
I guess we're safe.
I'm not sure.
This feels weird.
Oh, shit!
How is this not...
Okay, maybe, maybe my machine doesn't even trigger them.
Dude, I discovered the ultimate thing.
I can actually follow it.
I can't wait to see what goodies is in those chests when we're done with this.
Haha, this is so fucked.
Wait, there's one over there!
Is it gonna generate bubbles?
Don't do it.
So, right now I'm close to the machine, so maybe the noise it makes counts as my noise?
Let's find out, shall we?
It's not...
Yeah, look, it's not going to that!
You see that?
Diamonds, but I can't mine that, unfortunately.
It's gonna alert everyone.
See, why did you stop now?
I don't like that.
Can I take you without alerting?
Okay.
Chest!
We're safe.
Swift sneak!
Awesome!
And we got this disc fragment.
I'll take some books, too.
You can have this.
Regeneration.
Oh, I definitely want one of these.
I need to bookmark this place and come back.
So we know the sound is safe here.
That's the wrong one!
This one alerts.
This one doesn't.
Oh, God.
Please start.
Shit!
Oh, my God.
What am I doing, man?
This is the last dig.
After this, we're gonna stop and come out.
Fuck!
Why did it stop?
Can I?
Shit!
Don't tell me he's gonna come.
What was that sound?
You heard that?
Someone went like...
I think it's time to leave.
I have infringed enough upon this place.
Oh, I thought they were like enemies.
But it's just blocks.
Okay, I wanna leave.
I wanna get out.
I don't like this.
We gotta come back with night vision.
That's really it.
All we gotta do, but...
Where did I come from?
Oh, wait.
I remember this.
There's a chest!
We gotta try and get that.
I see another chest, too!
Oooh!
Okay, let's say I open this chest and all hell breaks loose.
What do I do?
I guess I just fly.
But I need to empty my inventory first before.
Just in case I need to quickly rob.
Honestly, I don't care about that.
A stack of four on the side?
Who cares?
That's fine.
We don't need this.
We don't need this right now.
We don't need that either, honestly.
The rest is good.
Man, I don't like any of that.
Let's go to the other chest.
Maybe there's always chests in these weird structures here.
Wait, I don't have any blocks now.
Oh, we got a dude.
Oh no!
This may not be feasible.
Yeah, we got bubble generators.
But we're so high up, maybe it's fine.
I'm gonna get some of these.
Wish me luck.
Worst case, we fly away.
Okay, so we're right above it and that didn't trigger anything.
Oh, nice!
Looting and power.
Soul torch.
Yeah, we can disenchant that.
I'll take it.
Some coal is always good.
I don't have room for this stuff.
Do I... I don't even think I want it.
Honestly, I don't want this.
Okay.
Now we leave.
We squoze the lemon.
Oh wait, that's another chest.
We can do one more.
I think we're good.
Nice!
Oh my...
Look at his hole!
That's a crazy hole!
We got a music disc too!
And insane leggings!
Oh...
The greed is paying off.
Very nice.
What do I not need here?
Honestly, this didn't trigger anything up here, so...
I guess it's not useful.
Don't need the lever.
We do actually need the lever.
Don't need the rails.
Man, I wish I brought my toolbox.
Really do.
Now, I feel like I should keep looking.
Like, this has just been paying off like crazy so far.
I see diamonds up there, but whatever.
Nah, let's leave.
Let's leave.
That was it.
We're done.
Should be safe here.
In fact, I leave in style.
I hate that it's so dark here.
Huh?
Okay.
Not interesting.
Right here.
And that may not even work.
Boy.
Keep unlocking things here.
Uh...
Maybe it works.
It works.
We're going.
Bye-bye.
I'm not sure how to even bookmark this place.
One way to do it would be to always have a...
uh... loadstone with you.
And a compass so that you could, you know...
link up that compass to the loadstone and then find your way back.
That's...
one way to do it.
But it does require some netherite.
Which is hella expensive.
Digging so slow.
Diamonds.
Do need that.
Let's see what it's picking up here.
Oh my god.
Chests are full, huh?
Let's see the other side.
Not... no diamonds?
Really?
Uh... I'll take this.
No...
Am I?
Hey, you know what?
Why am I not just filling up these chests with things I don't need?
Hello?
You kidding me?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
This is like genius.
Why didn't I think of this?
That's obviously the thing I need to do.
Nuts.
Wait, there's more here.
This is a crazy cave.
Okay, maybe I have seen these before actually.
Now that I see it like that.
This does look kinda...
familiar.
Oh!
Chest!
I gotta get it.
Sick.
Ooh, more fragments.
A music disc.
Sweet.
I feel like we should keep looking around a little bit.
If we see a chest...
I'm just gonna quickly snatch it.
Oh, that's where I was before over there.
Okay, I think I'm good.
Let's see what the digging machine is doing.
It's digging!
No surprise.
And then I can put in all this stuff.
Yep.
There's gonna be so much experience up front, I think.
Let's see.
Let's let the pickaxe suck it up.
No, that wasn't that much.
Wait, where's that coming from?
It's like underground somehow.
Was that diamonds maybe?
Maybe it mined some diamonds.
It's going so slow.
Oh, by the way, the main reason I wanted to dig in the first place...
was to find...
andesite and diorite.
Which I think I'm a little too...
deep for right now.
I need to go a little higher up for that.
But it's cool that we found that other place.
Oh, that was my first stack.
Give me...
another one.
There you go.
What's going on here?
What's up, guys?
Isn't this thing gonna come through the...
Yeah, look!
So cool!
Wait, I can ride it, right?
I guess if I have a better spot, I could ride it.
A lower spot.
Did you find some diamonds, son?
Could be that it's stacking the diamonds somewhere else first.
Oh!
Look at that!
21 diamonds!
It's definitely finding diamonds.
Wow.
Getting so much...
More diamonds!
This has to be the way to get diamonds.
I'll even take this.
Now that we have infinite storage.
Dude, this...
The fact that I can bring infinite storage with me...
is kinda crazy.
It feels a little bit weird that I can do that.
Like, why would I ever bring a toolbox now?
When I have this.
Also, with all the coal we're finding...
Well, not right here, but...
We're gonna be able to...
Blast a lot of the...
Copper and stuff when we get home.
Manually, in the blasting furnace.
Because that gives us experience for doing it.
Oh, more diamonds.
Don't mind if I do.
That's a lot, too.
Ooh!
Sweet cakes.
More!
Wow!
What am I gonna use all this diamond for?
We're gonna expand this digging machine to be even bigger and better.
And then take it to the nether.
And we're gonna wear a sweater.
And we're all gonna do it together.
Whoa!
Oh my god!
Look at this place!
It is massive!
Oh, we got a child.
Little fucking...
Aw, they're so tough!
Little bastards.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
Leave me alone, leave me alone.
I will put you in the digging machine.
Wait, are those endermen?
I think they are.
What are they doing here?
They did not like me coming in here with my industrialism.
Did I stop digging?
No, it's continued.
Okay.
Look at this crazy cave, man!
It's so tall!
Wish I had night vision right now so I could see this properly.
Should be wary of these, uh...
Creepers here.
They could fall down on me and cause...
Problems.
And dying right here would actually be the most catastrophic thing that could ever happen to me.
So we really gotta keep an eye out.
Also, are we still running out of space here at all?
Not really.
Oh, it's digging fast.
We hit tough.
Tough is not that tough.
It's kind of a misnomer.
How much diamond?
20...
Okay, we're not finding that many more diamonds now.
Rail...
No, train...
Right.
We're actually getting everything we need to do the train today.
I really don't want to die here.
Do I have blast protection?
No, I don't.
Would love to have a lot of that against the creepers.
Because that is realistically the only thing that could really fuck up my day real fast.
Like this.
Openings in the ceiling scare me.
Close that shit off.
Open space.
Let's stay back a bit.
What's out there?
I think it's time to head home.
Oh, it's a...
Thingy.
Oh, lava!
Nope!
No, no, no.
Don't run off a cliff there.
I guess it could make a bridge.
Then we had lava over there as well, so that's kind of bad.
Oh, did I lose my arrow?
Shit.
I think it's time to leave.
Let's get out of here.
I'm gonna dig straight up.
Because I'm a real G.
See ya!
Guys, it's going to be day when I reach the surface.
And you can quote me on that.
Not gonna be a while until we do, though.
Guys, if it's day when I reach the surface, I'm going to stream tomorrow again.
If it's night, I'm not gonna stream for a whole week.
Get ready.
Don't even want to look around.
Actually, I do want to look a little bit.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
It's been a while, huh?
Been a while since you did that to me.
Phew.
I almost forgot that was a thing.
Get ready for day.
Stream tomorrow.
Yikes.
You know what this means, right?
I'm probably gonna stream anyway.
Because I don't let random events dictate my existence.
That's right.
Fuck the bitrate.
What's that?
Is that lava?
Has to be, right?
Yeah, it's lava.
Wait, is that the same tower?
How am I here?
That's crazy.
Isn't it?
I do want to try and find another igloo.
Let's go to bed.
You can't find an igloo on an empty stomach, right?
So we go to sleep first.
Okay, guys.
I need you all to be on the lookout for an igloo.
And if you do see one, really make it clear in chat, okay?
Wait, we got one!
Unless that's the same one.
There's no way.
Oh!
God dang.
I'm gonna find another igloo.
There's sand here for some reason.
That's kind of odd.
Oh, those are pumpkins.
Speaking of pumpkins.
I was considering buying one the other day and then carving it for Halloween.
Maybe we should do it.
Oh!
Would you look at that?
I'll take some obsidian.
Because check it out!
I am just gonna...
Wait, where are my tracks?
Oh, I can't pull this out unless we have tracks!
Well, that's a bummer.
Guys, I predict inside here...
there's going to be...
a fortress.
Wait, can I even light this thing?
Yes, I can.
Why am I always forgetting the frickin' shape of this?
Like there, right?
No fortress?
No, no, no, it's here, it's here.
I'm never wrong.
Wait, I'm wrong?
I'm not used to this.
But... but...
I'm always right.
Huh, so that's how that feels.
Being wrong.
Had to have him sooner or later, right?
Let's go back in.
I guess we just keep flying.
How's my durability?
It's great, we're chilling.
Uh, igloo hunting.
Let's really look now.
Are you looking?
I hate...
the possibility...
of the igloo being inside like a forest.
Because if it is, I will have no chance to see it.
From the air.
Maybe I'll walk through it a bit.
We'll see how it goes.
Wait, are these ferns?
Oh, I guess I can't check.
No, these are ferns.
These are ferns.
A little village.
This can never be an igloo, I don't think.
Yeah, they look like igloos, but they're fake.
Now, what are these guys eating though?
Oh wait, we should get cats.
I don't even have any cats.
But we need fish for that.
Yo, what are y'all eating in this village?
I guess fish, maybe?
Maybe that's why you also have cats?
Brother, what?
No chests?
What are you?
Some kind of hunter or something?
How come I can't...
Oh, maybe that's just your standard look.
We keep moving.
Keep looking for igloo.
I'm looking at chat!
I stopped looking.
I'm gonna look again in 10 seconds.
Wait, where's the goddamn igloo?
Show me the igloo, damn it.
Oh, that's so stupid.
Hey, that's so picturesque!
Look at that little green island there!
Yo!
I kinda wanna have a little hut.
Also, we're running low on rockets.
Maybe it's time to start hitting home.
That way.
That's so nice looking, man.
Very pretty.
What's that?
It's ice.
Ice baby.
Maybe.
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do.
Ah...
Let's start going home.
And then we look for igloo on the way.
Wait, am I really back at that same tower?
I'm going in circles.
How is this possible?
What is that?
Hold the phone.
I've seen something like that before.
Abandoned village.
Cats?
Where?
You're down there.
What's going on?
Village is reopened.
Someone left in a hurry.
What's behind their bread?
I mean...
Come on, guys.
They have two basins of water here, right next to that bread basket.
Oh.
Oi, oi, oi, oi, oi.
This is an infected villager.
Unfortunately, I can't do anything about that.
I don't have the necessary requirements.
I see money.
Oh, nice.
So what the hell is this place even?
Why am I so intrigued by it?
Oh, let's actually go to bed.
Ah!
Oh, God.
How the...
How the hell do I get out of this?
Hello?
Are you kidding me?
Oh, okay.
Okay, here we go.
Here we go.
Jesus.
It's like impossible to get out of.
What a weird place.
Oh, that's so green looking.
After you've seen all this white, you know?
There's still a chance we find an igloo.
We keep our eyes peeled.
I have to.
I can't not do it.
Also, I will take this.
Wait, it works next to ice?
Interesting.
Silk touch.
Ah, wait.
I don't have enough obsidian for this.
I can't even light it.
Yeah, okay.
Whatever.
Never mind.
Okay, igloo time.
Come on.
Show yourself.
I really need this recipe.
What?
Oh.
Rabbits.
It should be easy to see something here.
But no.
Ten rockets left.
A little village.
Show me the glue.
They are so incredibly rare.
What's that?
It's a weird tree.
Hey, you know what?
Maybe these guys have carrots.
I kind of need that.
Would be nice to get that on the way home, too.
Looks like a carrot village to me.
It's hard to explain why, but it just does, you know?
Damn, that's expensive.
Think I'm made of money?
Looks like bread people.
No carrots here.
What are you doing on the roof?
You're unemployed.
Pumpkin pie.
I'll eat that.
Could have been special.
But it wasn't.
Alright, let's leave.
Oh, wait.
Are we close to home?
This may be the village right next to my home.
I recognize this.
I was here to grab ferns.
Should be right on the other side of this mountain.
Yep.
Oh, that's cool.
Love this new compass.
It's huge.
Okay, we brought home the goodies, though.
Holy crap.
We got so much.
Let's start processing.
Need tracks first, though.
Or rails.
Just one.
Actually.
And then it's time for trains.
No, but really, this time it is.
Like, 100% time for trains.
I promise you.
We're doing trains.
Let's start, uh, blasting.
Uh, don't I have, like, a million coal?
I should have.
Oh, oh.
I...
Unintentional washing sequence.
The question is, do I want to be lazy and blast it in bulk?
Or do I want to be logical and gain experience from it?
That's the question, isn't it?
I think we don't really need it right now, so it's okay to just blast it in.
Or, like, uh, blast it in the furnace here.
Yeah.
Sounds good to me.
There's no rush.
And...
Then I think it's time that we start disenchanting.
Uh, actually.
Hold on.
This is actually a great helmet for the nether.
Fire protection on that.
I'll keep it.
Delicious pumpkin pie.
Also, I'm going to put my safe spot here.
There we go.
So, one money.
I think that's in here.
Bed and boat.
Shield.
Never even used a shield.
So, these golden items here, we can actually crush them.
Right?
Hold on.
Golden shovel.
Oh, no.
We can blast it.
Oh.
Uh.
Okay.
But, uh, it's going to be tough to collect, though.
Ah, annoying.
Put this in there.
Obsidian.
61 diamonds, bro.
That's a lot.
Look at that experience.
It's not a lot, but it's something.
There.
Lever.
It's in here.
Carton assembler.
We don't need that anymore.
I'll leave the compass here, too.
Unless it's something I should always have on me.
Uh.
Yeah, actually.
Oh, my God.
Look at all this.
So, hold on.
Nether rack?
Crushed?
Gives me something cool.
I believe.
Am I blind?
Where the hell is it?
What's coming out of that?
Cinder flower.
And cinder flower can be used with other ingredients to make, like, gunpowder or something.
You know, like, you can do a lot of stuff with that.
That's quite nice.
That.
Uh.
Score.
I don't know if that's exotic.
It doesn't seem exotic to me.
There we go.
Blackstone.
And now we have this.
So, I'm gonna put the compass in here.
Along with...
Oh, you know what?
How about we make the equipment box the exploration box?
Meaning we have, like, stuff like the boat, the bed, the bucket, you know?
All these things.
And we don't care about the stacking thing.
Don't need it right now.
We can even put a suit of, uh, cardboard stuff in there.
If we need to be sneaky.
But that is four slots.
One, two, three, four.
And then the bed.
Yeah.
That could be the setup.
Let's do it.
That's now my exploration setup.
And we're always gonna carry that around.
Right there.
Um.
Yeah.
And I guess the shield I will...
Uh, actually, I would love to have a shield in that box, too.
But nothing would stop me from having two toolboxes.
You know?
And then I can leave one at home.
And then when I go exploring, I just take the toolbox.
In fact, I can even...
Do this.
So that when I go exploring, I go like...
Yoink!
And then I'm off.
Because I know what's in there.
That's the new way to do it.
I like it.
This is done.
Let's cook some more.
There you go.
Now, with all this...
Iron.
And let's not forget all the stuff we have out here.
It's time to make a bunch of rails.
Let's just...
You know?
Mess this up.
Now we're gonna have to do it like this.
Wonderful.
It's all gonna get crushed.
And, um...
God, what was I thinking just now?
Something I was thinking.
What was it?
I have no idea.
Oh, we also have all this.
Oh, that's an amazing hole.
There's my arrow that I was missing.
I would say...
Miscellaneous.
Kind of need a second miscellaneous chest.
Oh, and we also have some train tracks here.
I'm taking those.
Oh, let's put this in here.
It's also nice.
That goes in...
What's my other hole?
Oh, maybe I lost my other hole?
So I actually have a fantastic one now.
For replacement.
This one's gonna get disenchanted for sure.
Oh, music discs.
Put them in here for now.
I would say that's more like equipment and utility stuff.
These iron leggings can...
Get crushed.
Swift sneak.
Wow, running out of space here.
All this raw copper we can start cooking here.
That's the experience for me.
And we grab these tracks.
Now, for the train.
I think it was stone slabs and...
iron nuggets.
Oh, I think we actually have a little problem out here.
That's what I was gonna do before that I forgot.
Yeah, look at this.
That's the problem right now.
There we go.
Fixed.
And now we close this up so we can't have that happen again.
You really want to stand in front of the digging machine, huh?
That's brave.
Lucky for you it wasn't on.
Ran it in there.
I do want to cook this iron first, actually.
The
flower.
Now, cinder flower...
I'm gonna call that exotic from now on.
Because it is kind of exotic.
Now, we need stone.
Lots of stone.
I believe...
Train...
It's just stone slab.
There we go.
That's a lot.
And then we have a bunch of iron nuggets we can make now as well.
I even think we have the infrastructure already to make the tracks.
Because we have it set up over here.
What's up, piggy?
Let's see.
So, it's two hands.
Isn't it?
Or is it two presses?
Two hands and a press.
Yeah.
This is it right here.
We even...
Oh my god.
That's perfect.
Fill that up with that.
Now, ideally, we should have a little chest on top of each of these.
But I don't think it actually takes from the chest directly.
We have to put a funnel, actually.
Yeah, I think it's funnel time.
Either that or hopper.
And then we just fill them up.
So, I need...
I need...
These.
And if that doesn't work...
We're gonna bring these.
These.
Okay.
That's all we need.
Because then we can really fill it up.
Oh, chests.
I need chests.
Good thing I remembered.
One.
We can definitely make more.
Let's just make a bunch so we have them.
Oh, wait.
The torch is not gonna get me anywhere.
Let's try this first.
Hey.
That's pretty cool, actually.
I think it's working.
But is it just going in the chute or...
No, it's working.
It's working.
Unbelievable.
Oh!
That's a lot of train tracks coming in, boys.
Oh, yeah.
That's gonna keep working.
That's fantastic.
And now we gotta start working on combining a bunch of diorite and cobblestone that we brought home...
To create a bunch of andesite.
That's the next step.
Diorite.
Let's get all the diorite that we have.
There must be more.
There's a little here.
There's some there.
That's it, huh?
Okay.
That's fine.
We have some cobblestone.
And let's see how much we can make of this.
We can just make it manually, right?
Andesite.
Ooh, yeah.
Oh, my God!
Dude!
This is, like, Christmas.
I'm so happy.
This is also done soon.
And we can plop in the sink.
Now, with all of this andesite, of course we're gonna make...
Ah, but wait.
Nuggets.
Alloys.
Oh, we're making alloys.
A lot of alloys.
Now I really need this to finish, so I can put this in there.
Level 20.
There you go.
There's actually more.
I also think I found a bunch of iron.
Wait, did I have iron on me?
I did.
So we can make a bunch of these.
I will never run out of this again.
I am so happy that we have all this.
That was a quick affair.
All that iron is gone in a jiffy.
I guess I should maybe save the rest of the iron that comes out here.
We also have a bunch of cobblestone we can turn into iron.
Let's do that.
Now, question.
I also brought home a bunch of crazy shit.
For example...
Cobbled deepslate.
Can I do anything with that?
Wait, really?
Nothing?
Cobbled...
Wow.
Okay.
Well, what about tough?
Nah.
Okay.
I was hoping for, you know, some crushing action here.
What about granite?
We mill it and we get red sand.
Interesting.
What's that good for?
Oh, yeah.
I guess we can make glass out of it.
That's kind of dope.
Yeah, alright.
Why not?
Oh, what about crimsite?
Ah, we tried to check that already.
Crimsite.
Wait, we got...
Oh, check it out!
All this wool came from, uh...
Uh, the dark place.
Forget the name of it.
There's a name for it.
The, um...
The city.
Underground city.
And all this wool we can probably use to make a bunch of windmills.
This is actually huge.
And I kind of like the color of it, too.
This is a nice wool.
Good, uh...
Fabric.
Let's crush some more of this.
Let's see how much we already got.
It's coming in, look.
I mean, it's coming in.
It's coming in.
With all this andesite alloy, I forgot what I was using that for.
We needed it for something.
Was it the drill?
To make an even better drill?
Oh yeah, it was.
And of course, ironing it.
So we really should be saving up some iron now, too.
Now, for the train.
Let's start laying down some tracks.
Uh, clean up inventory first.
I feel like we need a wool chest or something.
Like, uh...
Fabric chest.
Everything fabric related.
Like...
Like wool.
Ha ha ha.
And maybe some, uh...
Yeah, well, it's...
It's a wool chest.
I also do need a couple more nameplates here.
Or, um...
These things.
Signs.
Give me that.
Wait.
Uh, sink ingots?
Oh, we can turn these into freaking thingies as well, of course.
Right.
Yeah.
I should have done that instead of using my iron.
I didn't even realize.
Whoops.
It's okay, though.
Put all this in here instead.
Also, the difference between crushed raw copper and...
Raw copper?
What was the difference?
Okay, you can get some clay out of that.
Huh.
I guess we can put it in here and get experience, too, from it.
Not bad.
Way too much flint, though.
Like, we really need to cut back on that.
And use it for something.
Something different.
I mean, yeah, this...
Obviously.
This...
Man!
We gotta figure this out with the lava.
I'm trying to think how we could do this.
Lava.
So, we need a continuous supply of lava going in.
Which means we gotta keep sucking.
From, like, a lake of lava.
I mean...
And if we go to the nether, then we have to stay in the nether for that to happen.
Oh, man.
I have no idea.
No clue.
It would be such a nice way to get andesite, wouldn't it?
I think we're running out of a stone chest.
We need a more...
We need more stone chest.
Maybe this one.
This is now the andesite chest.
And I will not forget it.
But there's stuff in here now.
Let's go check on the tracks that we made.
There should be a lot.
Oh, my...
God!
Are you ready?
The train revolution is coming.
Wait, what's the limit here?
Ah.
It's gonna be the ultimate train ride.
I wonder how fast we can go with the train.
Maybe you can really speed up, you know?
Go omega fast.
Here come the bridge!
I'm so excited about this part.
We need to get a little more dirt or stone, I think.
Let's go grab some stone for that.
This is so lazy.
I mean, it's not a big deal.
Let's try it.
Let's have a look, shall we?
Oh.
Not an easy way to get up there.
I guess here.
Now to remember how this works.
I completely forgot how this works.
Oh, maybe that's it?
Oh, that's it!
Uh, we have a little sheep in the way.
Sup?
Oh.
Did he survive?
Why is it, like, bugging?
Oh, never mind.
It's not.
Oh, now we're going a little slower.
Sup, fool?
Okay, that's pretty dope.
I wonder...
Why is it lagging, though?
Like, it's not smooth motion.
You see that?
Kind of annoying.
Going backwards is not good.
Like, it's super slow backwards.
But I guess we would have to have a...
a front car on the other side, then, we can pull with.
I mean, that's how trains work in real life.
You have one on each side that pulls, right?
You don't actually go backwards.
Get off the road!
Okay, here.
And the way we stopped it...
There we go.
Okay, not bad, not bad.
Now we gotta go get some stones.
To make a bridge.
I'm excited about that now.
Stone bricks.
Cracked stone bricks, and...
We also need mossy stuff.
Look how much I got.
How do I make the...
bricks again?
Oh, I just make them.
Alright.
Maybe we take some of these as well.
Bit of everything.
Maybe some slabs.
I don't know why you would do that, but I'm doing it anyway.
We can even have some wall.
We need to.
And I'm trying to think what else.
So to make this, we need moss block.
Don't I have that?
Moss block.
Alright, I guess I don't.
We gotta go find some.
Anything else?
I think that's it!
Let's go ride the train again.
I kind of want to attach another car up front, actually.
Oh, how the hell did I do this?
Oh, God.
Wait, why can't I disassemble?
Oh, we need this, I think.
How come this is not?
Oh, is it...
Like a track to relocate?
Oh!
Huh!
Okay, that's cool.
You can do that.
I think we need a train casing here.
I actually have it.
I got too much stone.
Because we gotta be able to come back quick, too.
And not go slow when we go the other way.
Train casing.
Maybe bring a train station.
We also do have quite a bit of tracks.
Uh, don't need this right now.
Okay.
Oh, I can't even ponder that.
And place the station nearby.
Yeah.
Train casing's on tracks.
Right.
And then super glue.
Yeah.
Assemble trains will move fast if they can find fuel.
Oh!
Really?
Okay, we gotta do that.
I got fuel.
Somewhere.
Maybe here?
I'll take that.
Oh, nice.
Bunch of snacks.
But let me try this.
So, the thing that's confusing me.
Like, why can't I disassemble the train here again?
Oh, I think I had to hold a button or something.
To, like, let it roll into station, remember?
There was something like that.
Train requires train controls.
When used on a station maps, we'll add a labeled marker.
This is way too...
Oh, my God.
How the hell...
Oh!
I can't read it!
What does it say?
Hold...
Space!
There we go!
Oh, shit!
Oh, God.
Go back, go back, go back, go back.
Okay, now...
There we go.
And now we can disassemble.
And now we make another bogey?
Uh...
In the back here.
Running out of space.
Stop bonging the bongo drum!
Go!
Get it!
Get!
You're free!
Get out of here!
Thank you.
Okay, now...
There we go.
That's very annoying.
I don't have patience for that.
We're gonna get the hole.
Not that one.
The good one.
Okay.
So this guy is gonna look like that guy now.
We're gonna make the same design.
We also do need controls.
Oh, shit!
We need that for that!
Do I have one?
That is such a tough one to make.
Precision.
Yeah.
Small wheel, big wheel, iron nugget.
And gold plate.
Oh, god.
Okay, you know what?
Put all this stone back for now.
We're not gonna need it right now.
Wait, chests.
I'll go over here.
No, we need the chests.
The whole point was to use the chests.
Greenery.
Okay, okay, okay.
Now.
Wood.
Slaps.
And then the controls.
So we gotta go bring small wheel, big wheel, iron nugget.
Big wheel.
Small wheel.
I think I have this set up already over here.
It's the one that throws the items back, you know?
Yeah.
It's already sort of doing it.
I'm gonna grab these when they come.
Oh, but wait, we actually...
Oh, no.
We're missing a bunch of things here.
I think we need two hands.
Two hands.
No, three hands.
Three hands.
Okay.
It's not too bad.
Also, we gotta put these gold bars to press.
I'm pretty sure I already did that.
Where did they go?
Didn't I have a bunch of gold bars being pressed?
Or...
I think actually that was...
Copper.
It was not gold.
Yeah.
Let's do that.
And...
So we're gonna put that to work.
And we need the hands.
One, two, three.
We're not gonna have the torque for it over there, so we're gonna have to disassemble other parts of the machine.
But that's...
Oh, this one is also not the right one right now.
You need a depot there.
I can find it.
There.
There you go.
You go to work.
Why are they red?
I don't know.
There we go.
This is...
Assemble the rest.
I should have brought shafts, maybe.
We're probably gonna need it.
Wait, why are there only...
What happened there?
No, we...
Oh, we do it here.
Oh!
The doggo went flying!
Alright.
I feel like I should make a new one.
Like, this is already doing something else.
And we need power.
I guess I can use my...
little engine that could.
So we set that up.
Then we need the thing that throws it back.
Ejector.
That's what it's called.
All this just to make that damn train.
Like, it's insane how much you need to do.
Cockwheel depot and sheet.
I may not have another depot.
Oh, wait, never mind.
I do.
Sheet we have now.
There.
And we're also gonna need a little bit of rubber.
And some rods.
That's pretty much it, I think.
Oh, and then some power.
And...
the power...
Uh...
I guess we can have water flowing.
Probably the easiest.
Right now.
Some quick power.
That does require water flowing, of course.
Let's do something cheeky.
We're gonna make a little flow ourselves.
Right here.
Yeah.
I just need some dirt, though.
There we go.
We're gonna set up a little...
Ah, but wait.
We also need depots, don't we, for that?
Oh, I have them.
No, wait.
We don't.
Because we're gonna use a belt.
It's fine.
Yeah.
We're chilling.
I'm gonna set it up over here.
Next to the factory.
So what we have here...
We're not gonna power from this side anymore, because we're running out of power.
We're gonna have it over here instead.
In fact...
Isn't this water gonna spread in multiple directions if I open up a little path here?
I do really like this design.
It's so cool, you know?
Water comes flowing down like that.
But, you know what?
That's for later.
Let's make a quick and dirty one.
We're cheating a little bit here.
Why are you following me?
Stop.
That's a big old wheel.
I think I may have used...
Like, there's no reason to use this big a wheel for this.
Right?
Whatever.
It'd be spinning.
It's not the prettiest, okay?
It's not supposed to be.
We ideally want that in...
Ah...
Man.
Okay.
Hey, actually, no.
It doesn't even matter.
We're gonna have to make it spin faster anyway.
There.
Wait, that doesn't even make sense.
So, this is the right height now.
But...
We wanna do this instead.
Wait, why is...
Wait, why do I always fucking forget which way is which?
Take the big wheel...
Into smaller, into bigger.
Yeah.
This is so unintuitive for me.
And then a big one.
But I wanna keep the same height.
Ideally.
This is the perfect height right now.
Honestly, maybe the speed is fine.
You know what?
I'm just gonna leave it at that.
That's a good speed.
I like it.
Good speed.
And let's not forget, we also need to...
Move that across.
So...
Yeah, let's just keep it simple.
Use multiple smaller.
Like that.
This one needs that.
These ones need...
It's all the same.
Perfect.
Now we have two hands.
Oh, wait.
We need three hands.
Yeah.
What the...
There we go!
Now for some shafts.
Uh...
I guess we should take that rotation and bring it down here.
Can extend this slightly.
Good enough.
Actually, even better.
There.
Get rid of this tree.
Oh my god, it's a tall boy!
Why are you so tall?
I hate when you're tall.
Now for the belt.
It's going the wrong way, but that's okay.
We just do it this way then.
Whatever.
It makes no difference to me.
Oh!
Oh, wait.
We don't need this.
Bro, I don't understand how this fucking works!
There we go.
So wait.
If I...
If I hit this side...
Oh, it's going around...
Okay, so wait.
Ah!
And now because I want to turn it...
Yeah!
Okay!
Okay, okay.
Hold on.
It makes sense.
Now I need funnels.
Why didn't I bring that?
Funnel me!
Funny.
All I had to do was just...
stop and think for a second.
How those things worked.
It's all about the axis of rotation.
Okay, uh...
So we have birch saplings.
We don't care.
What did I came back for?
Oh yeah, funnels.
Funnel, funnel, funnel!
Two.
Chests we already have.
So much work just to make a damn precision mechanism!
Wow.
The silly song is of course here.
Yeah, you better run.
Okay.
Fuck you.
Really should be using my bow.
It's even better.
This is painfully slow, isn't it?
I feel like we should have sped it up even more first.
Ah, whatever.
It's fine.
Okay.
So what was the order?
Small, big, nugget.
Nugget.
Big, small.
And input.
Ah, but wait!
We're not done.
We gotta throw it back.
And did I use a chute or something?
I used a hopper.
But can't I use a chute?
I feel like a chute would be kinda nice.
Wolf got cut in half by a mechanical saw.
Well, you idiot!
Why did you run into the saw?
That's on you.
That's kinda fucked up, actually.
Uh, what did I...
Oh, yeah.
Chute.
Ah, it's...
There's no way chute doesn't work.
Here we go.
So when this comes out here...
Oh!
Ow!
Wait a sec.
Wait, we don't need...
We don't...
Wait, we...
I could just manually put it in.
But, no.
I'm gonna put this thing on now.
Shoot here.
Oh!
No.
Let's not be lazy.
So, the way this works...
Wait, did it...
Oh, well.
Maybe it's because I'm...
Wait, there was a way to do this?
And it was kinda weird.
Show me.
Sneak.
Ah!
That should do it.
Gonna be a little slow...
Is that...
Oh, shit!
That needs rotation.
Good thing I have a wheel...
Somewhere.
Oh, god.
It's slow.
It's like geriatric precision...
Mechanism.
Oh, my god.
I regret not making it faster.
But, I mean...
It'll get the job done.
Right?
It'll...
It'll be fine.
It works.
It's doing it.
Gonna take a while.
Also, is it even guaranteed we get it?
80% chance only.
And a random salvage.
Alright.
We're making a lot, I guess.
May have to go make even more wheels.
Or cocks.
I need small, big, and more nugs.
And all this cobblestone is gonna...
Result in more nugs.
In you go.
How many nugs do I get?
I have 64 there.
That's good.
Now, I think we should bring even more chutes.
Put on top of each of those, so we can just fill it up from above.
And I do believe for cogs, we need the andesite thingy.
No, we don't even need that.
Wow.
Shafts and wood.
Super duper easy.
Actually, I wanna keep these.
A cog.
That's a lot.
Make a big one, and then a stack of that.
Why can't I make...
Oh, is it shaft?
Shaft shortage.
But shafts are easy to make.
That requires alloy.
Nice.
Very nice.
I'm gonna leave some of these here.
And we have one big stack, one big stack.
We got the chutes.
Just need...
Uh, three?
Also, we need more golden plates.
Let's turn these into...
These guys.
It's 12.
We're gonna smash them.
But it is good to have some gold around.
I think I have some...
On...
Oh, there we go.
We could really do with a hopper here.
On that one.
I mean, I had it...
I had this set up early, and then I destroyed it for some reason.
I'm sure there was a good reason that I destroyed it.
And that's about it, right?
So we...
Take these...
No, I...
You know what?
I'm gonna leave these at home.
Good to have some ingots at...
At hand.
That's it.
Looks like work has stopped here.
We filled this guy up with...
Oh, can I even...
I guess I'll just throw it in.
And the big ones...
And over here...
It's the nugs.
Why is it not working?
Hello?
Oh.
How come it's not...
Wait a sec.
I am so confused.
Oh, wait.
It is working.
Oh, okay, okay.
It's working.
Very nice.
It's just...
It's just taking a bit of time here.
It doesn't look like any of them have more progress than the rest.
Yet.
Maybe this new batch does.
I mean, it's working.
Yeah, there we go.
Okay, so it's just gonna take a while, I guess.
Even put that there.
I'm actually gonna put...
These down here, too.
I'm gonna be absorbed by that.
But now the thing is full.
That could be a problem.
Is it gonna stop, then?
Maybe not.
It's gonna be awkward, though.
You know what?
I'll take some of these...
And put them in here.
Yeah.
Otherwise, I think things are gonna be messed up.
We're gonna have a lot of precision mechanisms.
And who knows what we can do with that, then.
That's gonna be a lot.
Okay, I wanna try...
I need one precision...
I need just...
I need one.
Can we get, like...
Wait, which...
This is the most complete one, I guess.
Can I not just throw that on there manually?
Shit.
I don't...
I can't do it fast enough.
Oh, wait.
This is...
No.
Okay, you know what?
Just let nature run its course, I guess.
In the meantime, let's continue the tracks here.
And maybe work on the bridge a little bit.
In fact, I can just fly around and do it.
Now, this here...
Ideally, this would go through the factory.
But I don't like the angle of it right now.
So I'm just gonna work on the bridge.
This is gonna go to that village on the other side.
And I think what I'll end up doing, actually...
We're gonna turn that village into, like, a market.
You know, so that we can say...
I'm going to market.
I take the train, I go there...
And then we have all these villagers with different professions...
Giving me what I need.
I think that could be really cool.
So that's what I'm doing.
I need more tracks.
I need all my stone now.
Trains...
Yeah, I just keep that, I guess.
Now, all of this should already be sort of aligned here.
Beautiful.
Let's go.
Here we are.
Now, this portion, I think we can do with just dirt.
And then, you know, adjust it a little bit down the road.
Make it look nicer.
But for now...
This is dirt.
Then we reach this point.
And then starts the stone.
I will never figure out how this works.
I am...
Yeah.
Never will I figure that out.
Okay.
Now we use stone.
Now, which kind of stone?
I think bricks.
Maybe we have to make it a little wider.
Like this.
Nice.
I kind of like this being dirt here, maybe.
And then we wrap around like this.
Ran out of stone?
Really?
Okay.
I guess we're cracking it then.
Trying to make it look nice at the same time, you know?
We also need lights here, of course.
We're going to have some super nice lights.
Give me that.
Can I run out?
Man, I ran out.
Fully cracked now.
This part of the bridge has been here longer or something.
Ah, get up there!
Losing my mind!
Zombies are coming at me.
Okay, now we need a little bit more on this side.
Wait.
You know what?
Oh my god.
Do I set the digging machine on it, bro?
I can't believe it.
Oh, that's pain!
Piss off.
Brother, I...
Oh my fucking god.
Why wasn't I thinking?
This is...
This is so shameful.
I feel sick to my stomach.
Like, I could puke and vomit and cry.
Piss.
You know, I'm shaking.
It's just the worst.
Oh, you bastard.
I can't believe I've done this.
And now I'm gonna have to play a little bit of...
Avoid the creature in the water while collecting all this shit as well.
Can't wait for that.
This has to be, like, one of the top three worst feelings in Minecraft.
Having done something like this.
Alright, brother.
So I have to go collecting.
Take these first so they don't disappear.
Also, everything's fucking cobblestone.
No!
Get away from me!
Let me collect my...
Let me do my, you know, collection of shame here.
Wait, this is a weird look.
Look at this.
It's like...
I was perfectly on the edge of the water there.
What's going on?
No inventory?
Why is it always the silly song in these situations?
It's like the game is taunting me.
Give me that.
Okay.
Obviously, the bridge needed to be higher so that it's actually a bridge!
And we could go under it.
Now, how high?
I hate when the medicine comes in at the last moment just to, you know...
Just to really piss me off.
Don't you dare explode.
Assholes.
Let me build my...
Brash in peace!
Have I not suffered enough?
Okay, so...
Let's do it over here.
Maybe one lower.
Oh my god!
What was that?
Let me see.
I like that.
That's a good height.
Good height.
Leave me alone, you bastard.
You see what I mean?
The game is just fucking with me.
Like, I haven't seen these guys in ten years.
And when I'm about to build a bridge...
Where I really don't want to be disturbed like this...
Then they appear.
Insanity.
I'm gonna go into my inventory.
I'm also gonna have to, uh...
Cook a bunch of cobblestone now...
To make it into normal stone...
Because that got fucked up.
I guess I don't need this anymore.
Leave that here.
Are you kidding me?
Is there a guy out here?
Ah!
Go away!
You know what?
I'm gonna bring a bed with me...
So I can sleep over there...
In case it gets night again...
Because I can't stand that.
Oh wait!
That's my emergency box.
I got it.
Alright.
Copper ingot.
In.
Shaft.
We don't need those right now.
These fucking creeps...
This is like playing Terraria right now.
Okay.
So this is good.
That's good.
Cobblestone bad.
We take those and exchange.
Give me that instead.
I actually dig the normal stone.
It's nice.
Wait, wait, wait.
I could also make the bridge out of slabs.
Just thought of that.
Nah.
We're not gonna do that.
It would be...
Hmm.
Wait.
Let's at least preview it.
See what it looks like.
Let's not be so hasty.
There we go.
Full inventory.
As always.
Maybe we deposit some of this.
Nugs.
Don't eat the hole.
Okay.
Let's go.
Oh.
I'm bringing a bet.
But that was in my box.
Was it?
It was.
Alright.
Let's make this bridge.
Properly this time.
So here it's gonna go up.
Right?
And I guess...
Uh...
When the tracks come...
They're just gonna smoothly go up.
Which is awesome.
Yep.
That's it.
Now we add a bit of...
Sweetness to this.
Make it look extra nice.
And then we can come underneath with the boat.
Oh yeah.
Looking good.
That was nice.
Now it has to come down again.
And we're gonna go down...
Here.
Like that.
Don't I have more...
Just normal bricks?
Damn it.
I'll go get some.
Quite easy to make once you just have stone.
And I still have a lot of stone.
This bridge is gonna look so sweet.
I intend to put like a little railing on the side too.
Let's see what it looks like with the train tracks now.
Yeah.
I guess I have to...
Go on further back or something?
What?
Okay.
I guess I'll...
Do that instead.
Yeah.
That's pretty good.
We can even turn these into stairs on the sides.
Or something.
Let's see if this just goes down.
Dang, that looks pretty sick.
Now, I'm still not sure whether or not I want to use a stone wall here.
Or something else.
Jackie?
Come here.
You cannot be up there.
Okay.
How am I liking this?
Let me take a look at it from...
A bit further away.
It's not bad.
But it does look kind of samey.
Doesn't it?
We could maybe use grates.
Or maybe even something related to create here.
Could also be a possibility.
Or maybe even just wooden.
Because this is also kind of wooden looking.
Isn't it?
Like along here.
Even though it's not, I guess.
Metal.
But something...
To break up the color.
Slightly.
Let me actually go back and see what I have.
At hand.
I guess I'll try some...
Oak fence.
But I don't really have much wood.
Maybe it's time to go crank it a little.
What about grates?
Or not great.
What's it called?
The, um...
These ones.
It does cost a lot of iron.
Maybe not worth it.
Uh, bar.
What's that called?
Iron bars?
Can I not...
Can I not make copper bars?
I want to make copper bars.
Imagine that.
Let me see what else we got here.
You know, it sounds dumb.
But you could actually make a railing out of shaft.
And then break it up in between with some, uh...
Let's see how that looks.
I have an idea.
Do I really not have more?
Make more.
Wait, what?
Oh, I need wood, I guess?
Wait, what the fuck?
Oh, it's sink ingot.
Crazy.
Oh, that's a lot of shaft.
Shaft.
Maybe too much.
And I need this.
Okay, what do you think?
Is this gonna look good?
Maybe you see the vision?
We can even make them rotate.
To make it look kinda silly.
And fun.
Oh, I need to go to sleep.
There you go.
Now watch, this is what I had in mind.
And then in between.
Or we could even have the little, uh...
What are they called?
You know, the thingies, the wooden, uh...
Clamps, or whatever.
You know what I mean.
Let me see how this looks.
I mean, that's...
I feel like...
Oh my god, that looks pretty good.
That looks good.
I mean, this is also the same color as the stone, you know?
So...
The idea is there, just not for here.
Alright, we gotta go with wood.
It's...
It's obvious.
It's so good.
It actually...
It fits perfectly.
There's nothing else to say.
Wood it is.
Beautiful.
Okay.
Let's go crank that shit.
Ah, these ones.
Brackets.
Wooden brackets.
Those are the ones I talked about.
I'll bring them with me.
See how it looks.
I guess we don't need the walls anymore.
I have to...
I decided against that.
And...
Shafts.
Hand crank.
Okay.
No.
You know what?
Stop.
No more.
Alright.
We gotta stop here.
Save it.
It's already been so long.
Holy shit.
One half hours already.
We're gonna be cranking it next time.
And then we make that bridge.
And then...
I mean, I would say we did trains today.
We rode the train.
We have already made a significant portion of the train network.
The rest of the tunnel is made and we have a bunch of train tracks ready to go.
In the chamber.
And then I wanna experiment with...
Putting items on a train and unloading it.
We need, like, a distribution network.
And then we need a quarry somewhere where we just go crazy with a mining machine.
That's, like, the long-term plan with this.
Hey, Oliver.
Remember me.
Okay, person 74382.
You stand out a lot, you know?
I'll remember you.
I love joining right before the stream ends.
Aw, sorry.
I did stream very early today.
This was a kind of a...
Weird timing on this.
How could you kill your dog?
What do you mean, how could I?
I didn't do anything.
Did I jump in the saw?
That jump...
That dog decided...
To end its life.
I had nothing to do with that.
You think white holes exist?
I don't know.
Probably not in the way you think.
But, I mean, math does predict...
Or, I guess, physics does predict that there's, like...
Or it could be wormholes, right?
And if a black hole is sort of the entrance to one, you could maybe say the other...
I don't know.
Where were the safety measures?
The thing is, though, there's such a thing called common sense, you know?
And it seems like...
That dog just didn't have that.
Just get a hole and paint it white.
Easy.
What's the problem?
You know, there's actually a lot of magic tricks where you, like, paint a hole black.
And it looks like a hole to the human eye, you know?
You can really fool people with that.
Don't speak ill of the dead.
Yeah, you're right.
I shouldn't do that.
The thing is, though, I didn't specify that dog.
I just said dog.
There could have been any dog.
I don't know how many jumped in that, you know?
So it was kind of a vague statement.
Some people said that your bluebook mod doesn't work properly.
Like, it doesn't show recipe that I've only a percent of giving something.
I'll look into that.
I'll check it out.
A percent of giving something.
One sec.
You're talking about, for example, random salvage, right?
Stuff like that.
I'll look into it.
And also not fluids and items that you can only process.
Thank you for the feedback.
It's...
This is like what happens when you try to make a mod blind without being spoiled, you know?
It's kind of difficult.
But...
But it's good.
It's good that you guys are bringing this up.
I'll pass it along.
Can you add JEI mod?
It won't spoil...
No, I hate it.
And, yeah, like Lovine Nail said, it spoils everything.
It literally spoils everything.
There's nothing it doesn't spoil.
It's also very overwhelming.
Because it just adds everything, you know?
And it's like, what the hell?
You still remember Beampot?
Of course.
How could I forget myself?
Can't.
Haha.
There's a new dimension update.
What's that mean?
Will ODB return?
No!
There's only one ODB!
ODB...
Wait, did ODB die?
At some point?
Or did he survive?
I don't remember.
You're getting good at texturing?
Are you mean like, uh...
The cracked stone and all that?
I think so.
Regular Minecraft has an upcoming up...
Yeah, I know there's an upcoming update.
I mean, they update it all the time, right?
Yeah, don't tell me what's in the update.
At some point I'm gonna play it and it'll be fun to discover.
Yeah, G-game.
Somebody already pointed that out.
I'm gonna investigate.
I'll check it out.
When will you make Sorting Machine?
Ah, man.
Like...
I will make it.
It's just that...
It's like an insurmountable problem right now.
Because I already have all my chests set up, you know?
And it's gonna be...
It's like the real life.
It's like when you have chores to do in real life.
You keep setting it off, you know?
Or putting it off.
It's exactly the same thing.
Like, there's other things I also want to do.
So it's all about...
Prioritizing.
But I will do it at some point.
It's definitely...
A lot more...
Easy to do here.
But it's just about...
Doing it, right?
There's so much.
No, don't give me any hints.
Just...
Let me enjoy.
It's not gonna be any fun if you just tell me, right?
Is it like 4 p.m.
in Europe?
No, it's actually 2.30.
So almost 3 p.m.
But you're close.
One and a half hours off.
No, it's okay.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna try and see if I can fix that issue with the mod.
Yeah, we're always at 200,000 subscribers.
That's insane.
I mean, I think...
80% of that is gotta be Minecraft-related.
It's absolutely wild what's Minecraft...
Or what Minecraft has done for this channel.
It's wild.
No, there's mods today.
I see messages being deleted.
But I'm also pretty good at not reading them.
I mean, sometimes, you know, I'll read a spoiler.
And a lot of times, I don't even know what I'm reading, you know?
Yeah, the first season is legendary at this point for me as well.
So, just the memory of that is so nostalgic, you know?
I remember all my houses from that season and pretty much everything that happened, you know?
That will always be in my heart.
You forget it in three minutes.
Exactly.
Like, people literally told me how to respawn the dragon once.
Like, I was asking.
I was like, how do you do it?
And someone was like, here's how you do it.
And I was like, okay!
And now I have no idea how to do it.
But that was also years ago that people told me this, right?
So, I don't know, man.
I just don't remember that shit.
It must have been so random and...
I don't know.
Random and...
What's the word called?
Contrived or something.
That it just wouldn't make sense for me to remember that, you know?
Yeah, it's unintuitive, right?
I don't remember now.
Maybe I'll have you guys tell me, actually.
Because it was one of those things...
I do remember it was one of those things...
That I never would have discovered anyway, right?
On my own.
Like, it's simply...
It was one of those simply impossible things.
That doesn't make any sense at all.
Minecraft has a way of making you remember little things about your worlds for decades.
Right?
And you know what?
Here's why.
It's because you spent so much time with it.
The fact that you keep walking into your own home all the time...
It's just like real life, you know?
You will not forget the houses you've lived in.
Because you've just simply been there so long.
There's no difference between that and Minecraft.
You spent so much time building the houses and thinking about them, how to build them.
So obviously you're, you know, putting a lot of...
Memories into your RAM about that.
Which is why I know where everything is in World of Warcraft Classic.
I played World of Warcraft Classic GeoGuessr the other week.
And I nailed it, like, completely.
Because I remember every single freaking pixel in that game.
Because I spent so much time there.
Yeah, in the early days you didn't even have the recipe book in the game.
I can't even imagine playing like that, you know?
I guess it would be pretty much impossible.
But I kind of envy you guys.
The ones that played Minecraft back when it first came out and there was no recipe book.
And the way you sort of discovered things was talking to your friends.
You know?
It's like, everyone's playing this new game.
And they're all discovering it together.
And like, oh, I tried this.
Did you see you could do that, you know?
I feel like that could have been a cool experience to have as well.
Yeah, remember things and write them down and stuff.
Do you like Dinosaur?
I'd like to see you playing Ark.
It's a survival with Dinosaur.
It's my favorite game.
Maybe...
I mean, I'm not a dinosaur hater.
I can get behind dinosaurs.
But I'm not like a mega fan either.
I think Ark is already in my backlog, though.
But isn't that like a multiplayer PvP game or something?
Maybe I'm thinking of a different one.
Oh, I think I'm thinking of Rust.
Don't think there's dinosaurs in Rust, right?
Single player 2.
Okay.
You like island survival games?
That's such a specific question.
You say that as if there's a whole genre of that.
I have...
Like, I don't even know one island survival game.
You mean like being stranded on an island?
And then you start to, like, anthropomorphize a little basketball or something?
What is that movie?
Strand...
Castaway.
Sons of the Forest.
Is that an island survival game?
Or what?
Is it an island survival type game?
Stranded Deep also...
See, that one sounds like an island survival game.
The forest?
The forest is not an island.
It's a forest.
Come on.
Unless I am on an island with water around me, I will refuse to play it.
It needs to be an island survival game.
It's a forest on an island.
Okay, okay.
Then I'll consider it.
I just flat-out refuse to play games that aren't on an island.
That's just how I am.
There's a popular challenge in Minecraft called Skyblock, where you have to survive in a small island in the sky.
Yeah, I've heard people talk about this in the past.
I've heard the term Skyblock quite a few times, actually.
Is Minecraft technically island?
I actually don't know.
I guess...
It's just a bunch of islands?
Would you ever try a speedrun?
I actually would electric gelato.
I thought about making a series at some point, where it's just about speedrunning.
I think...
I'm actually kind of excited about that prospect.
It would be completely different to anything else I've done with Minecraft.
And, you know...
It would be fun to try and optimize it and stuff.
But I would do it in my own way, you know?
I wouldn't, uh...
I guess, in terms of, like, speedrun categories...
I would go for the category that is...
Without all the, like, weird external tools and stuff, you know?
Because the ones...
I've seen some videos where they just pull up all these weird fucking tools...
And it doesn't even look like Minecraft at all.
It's just weird to look at.
I would just play the game and try to beat it.
Fast.
How fast do you think I can beat Minecraft?
I think I can do it...
Okay.
I think I can beat Minecraft.
I'm trying to think of all the steps right now.
And how long it would take.
If I really, really try...
Maybe 50 minutes.
50 minutes.
5 hours?
Okay, some are saying fair.
You say no way?
Really?
Okay, mark my fucking words.
I can do it in 50 minutes.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Which difficulty are we talking?
Does it have to be hard?
Or, like, what kind of difficulty is it?
Difficulty doesn't matter at that point?
It does, though.
I feel like it does.
Most speedrunners use easy?
What?
What a bunch of cowards!
Look at me, I'm a Minecraft professional.
I speedrun the game, but I play it on easy.
What?
What do you mean?
Why aren't they playing on hard?
What the hell?
I mean, peaceful doesn't even have any enemies, right?
So it wouldn't make sense to play on that one.
If you don't get hit, then what difference does difficulty make?
Sure.
But, I don't know.
They're afraid of getting hit?
Then.
If you play on easy, right?
They do normal?
Okay, okay.
I don't know.
I'm getting conflicting answers on this now.
I guess I would play on hard.
If I'm doing a speedrun.
I feel like if you're doing a challenge anyway, why not just make it challenging?
But, I don't know.
I've not played Minecraft Dungeons.
It's in my backlog.
Your hunger gets depleted slower if you're on easy.
Yeah, it's easier.
Might as well do hardcore for extra swag.
Like, yeah, exactly.
If those guys don't get hit anyway, why not just play on hardcore?
Why are they playing on easy?
Well, because it's speedrun?
Okay, I see that argument, actually.
I can understand that.
If the argument is, you want to go as fast as possible...
Yeah, okay.
Okay.
I guess it makes sense.
If you go in with the idea that I want to beat this game as fast as possible...
So I will choose the difficulty that will allow me to do that.
Okay, yeah.
I see it.
I take it back, actually.
It makes sense.
I didn't think about it like that.
You changed my mind.
They changed difficulty during the run to manipulate mob aggro...
But they spent most time on easy.
Okay, see, that's some next level crazy shit.
This is what I mean.
Like, I will not be doing that, I don't think.
Like, if I do the speedrun stuff...
It would be like me trying to figure out how to optimize the run on my own, you know?
I think that could be fun on its own.
Because I really like doing stuff like that in video games.
Think of Factorio, you know?
Or even Minecraft Create.
So you're trying to make an item...
You have to optimize the production of it, right?
That process, to me, is fun.
So I think it could be fun to apply the same logic to, like...
Trying to beat the game faster.
Almost like a roguelite.
You know?
Might as well open setting and quit.
Why?
I mean, I know how to beat the game.
You beat the dragon, boom, you're done.
And you just gotta figure out you work backwards.
So how do you get to the dragon?
Oh, you go to the end.
How do you get to the end?
Oh, you get the...
The eyes, right?
Oh, how do you get the eyes?
And so on and so forth.
So you just try to optimize for that.
I think that could be fun.
Oh no, we've been talking for four hours.
We're about to start in a second here.
No, I'm kidding.
Actually, I'm out of here.
Thanks for watching.
This was an early stream.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Especially the people that can't make it to the normal time stream.
So I hope this was cool.
So yeah.
Have a wonderful Sunday.
Enjoy it.
I will see you around.
Bye-bye.